[Applause]
[Music]
n
I
[Music]
antic wonderful dance opening
performance ladies and gentlemen this
performance was brought to you by our
genz actaris from Prudential
Vietnam and we can feel the you f the
fresh and Fascinate that you bring to
our event today once again thank you all
so much thank
you ladies and gentlemen distinguished
guests speakers and Actuarial expert
from numerous domestic and international
insurance companies welcome to Vietnam
actuario conference
[Music]
2023 my name is tin Vu and I am
we are very honored and proud to
accompany actuar expert and insurance
professionals from domestic and
international insurance companies gather
here at the Vietnam actuo conference
today ladies and gentlemen Vietnam
actuar conference is the much awaited
annual Gathering of actuaries and
insurance professional operating in the
Vietnamese Market the conference is
Lively Forum to achain our acknowledge
and discuss insurance industry
challenges and Trends the VAC represent
the Actuarial Perfection dedication to
lifelong learning professional
development and public service where
every actuary in Vietnam aspire to be a
part of not just the knowledge and
connection they can gain but also for
the positive impact they can make on the
industry and the country as a whole the
Actuarial Society in Vietnam is growing
rapidly creating new opportunities and
challenges for the profession and
actuaries are no longer limited to the
conventional role of solving
mathematical problems they are also
involved in shaping the future the
emergence of young actuaries is making
the profession more vibrant and exciting
than ever before the energetic opening
Dan performance that we just witnessed
was performed by Young actuaries of
prenal Vietnam the performance conveys
the message that a Young Generation
giving their own playing to the fullest
breaking stereotypes with bondless
energy and Wes explore to open the next
era for the insurance
industry fential Vietnam has been a part
of the vietnames insurance Market since
1999 over the past 20 years of oper
ation potential has consistently and
unwaveringly promoted and supported a
culture of dedication with the aim of
generating positive and meaningful
values for
society potential Vietnam is very
honored to be the host of the Vietnam
Actuarial conference
2023 accompanying our attendees to
invade the team the next Insurance
era
Insurance business are constantly
developing and improving to a better
version customers are always Centric
city of our business Mission and along
with that partnership will be built on
Mission alignment and Trust to bring
customer the best experience when
participating in insurance and Now
ladies and gentlemen we are privileged
to welcome our distinguished guests to
our very special event today first of
all on site of Department of the
insurance supervisory Authority we are
pleased to welcome the presid
of please Jo me to give big round
Applause to welcome Miss Li Tut head of
life
insurance on S of Insurance Association
Vietnam we are pleased to welcome the
presence of Mr Chung the build Secretary
General of Insurance Association Vietnam
IV is also the silver sponsor for this
year event on site of the organizer
credential Vietnam we would like to
introduce Mr fman Chief security officer
of prudental
Vietnam and please welcome Mr mashad DOI
Edo appointed ay of presential
Vietnam
please welcome Mr J tan Chief marketing
officer of pro Dano
Vietnam and we would like to welcome
Miss D home height CH officer of brenal
Vietnam and on side of these sponsors we
would like to introduce Miss Elina Quake
representative of RGA Diamond
sponsor
please join us to welcome Miss ingber
representative of squid R the go sponsor
of this year
event please welcome Dr dir ner
representative of Genry ghost
[Music]
sponsor please welcome Mr Vasan iraia
ran stative of Pacific Life R the go
[Music]
sponsor would like to introduce the Pres
of Mr 22 representative of scoring S
silver
[Music]
sponsor please welcome Mr sunen K
representative of s oi the silver
[Music]
sponsor and please welcome Mr lman
representative of Munich re super
sponsor
and once again we warmly welcome all
Actuarial and insurance Professionals in
vietnames and international insurance
industry who are present in the seratin
conference Hall today once again please
give big round of applause to
[Music]
wo and Now ladies and gentlemen is our
greatest honor to invite to the state
Miss Li Tut representative of insurance
supervisory Authority Isa please come up
to the man State and share a few word
with all of us please
[Music]
welcome
hello
fore
for
[Music]
fore
for
spe
[Music]
may we invite Miss Le to remain on the
stage and move to the center and we
would like to invite M mashi Edo
appointed actually a potential Vietnam
representative of organizer to deliver
appreciation flower to miss
Li thank you so much Miss Li for your
attending today and for your great
speech Vietnamese Insurance Market is
still considered as emerging market and
there will still be many challenges to
overcome to achieve sustainable
development goals and in that Isa plays
a very important role in management and
supervision as well as setting the best
development direction for the market
thank
you and next we are honored to invite Mr
no Chung zung representative of
Insurance Association Vietnam please
welcome him to the
[Music]
stage
e
for
[Music]
foret
so Mr please on stage and now once again
we would like to invite Mr
Mas appointing actory of Pruden of
Vietnam representative of organizer to
present appreciation
flower booket to Mr go the iiv was
established in 1999 and is a reliable
home of all insurance companies iiv
always accompany insurance company in
all insurance commity and the Vic 2023
is organized thanks to the important
contribution of iib as a silver sponsor
thank
you and now lady ladies and gentlemen we
Cally invite Miss Elena quick
representative of RGA International
reinsurance Company our beloved Diamond
sponsor please come up to the men late
to share your thought for today's event
sincerely
welcome all right I'll try sing Chow
good morning good morning
everyone thank you so I hope you're all
feeling fresh all roaring and ready to
go and looking forward to a pack day of
you know knowledge sharing intriguing
conversations so I'd like to share with
you you know we how honored RJ is to be
the diamond sponsor for Vietnam actro
conference
2023 and to share a short story about it
it was actually a split second decision
from us um very evident and to be clear
and clear to us to be the diamond
sponsor and our friends at credential
can attest to it and the question why is
very simple because RGA has been
committed and is committed over the
years to work with our close Partners in
Vietnam together to Pro to give
protection solutions to our customers
and the families and together to close
the protection Gap it is also a
reflection of how vibrant We Believe
Vietnam Market is and the potential
growth it has and has yet to realize so
globally all around the world including
Vietnam we know there are Market
challenges there are economic challenges
but with all challenges it brings us
opportunities hence it is an opportune
time for the industry to start back to
the basics for the belief that we are
here to contribute to the betterment of
the society and to provide meaningful
full coverage to everyone by placing the
customers at the center of everything
that we do so at RGA we take pride in
putting families and communities at the
center of what we do and we don't just
say this in passing it is a core RJ
value of client
centricity and with clients in mind I
always remember one number and it is a
special number of over 50 million and
over 50 million is the number of
individuals and their families that RGA
provides Financial Protection to just
across southeast Asia alone and when we
saw the number it is a remarkable number
and something very close to our hearts
and again is not possible without the
support of our longstanding partners so
this is why I would like to thank
everyone here today for the close
partnership in helping us to deliver our
purpose of providing Financial
Protection accessible to all and looking
looking forward to the N Insurance era
being you know the theme of today's
conference what do you envision it to
be for me I Envision the nxs insurance
era to be one of tailoring it's
tailoring value propositions for
customers in their individual life
stages instead of a one-size fitall
solution and that together with product
sustainability so what is product
sustainability
being sustainable for the industry to
deliver the contract promise to our
customers so that they are provided the
financial protection and the peace of
mind for the lifetime of the policy that
we sold to them and you know they dearly
hold close to their H and they purchase
it to protect their family and loved
ones so I believe with this there is an
exciting n Insurance era that we can
partner and work together and look
forward to so with this I wish you and
thank you for having us here today and
wish you a fruitful conference ahead
thank
you may we invite Miss atena Quick to
Linker on the stage and we would like to
welcome Mr Chang ship marketing officer
of Vietnam of bral Vietnam to present
appreciation for to miss Elina quick
representative of RG International
reinsurance Company the diamond sponsor
for this year
[Music]
event
once again thank you so much Miss L
quick ladies and gentlemen prenal
Vietnam Assurance is a leading life
insurance company in Vietnam that is
committed to helping our customer
achieve their health and wealth goals we
operate with five core values ambitious
curious empathic courageous and nle
apparently the Sheep could not sell
without the leadership of our courageous
captain and let us now Cally invite to
the state the representative of our
events host Mr fman CEO of Pruden of
Vietnam Asin to Grace the state and
share his insight about the conference
please give Big R to
[Music]
Walker
[Applause]
for
Vietnam I'd like to thank um the
generosity of our Diamond sponsor a our
go sponsor Pacific library janry swiety
and the sil
[Applause]
[Music]
sponsor
everything everywhere all as
one
Rotten
Tomatoes
dead dead life
fore
everything everywhere all at
once
spee
fore fore
speee
stretch
London
foree
for
um
persistency
fore
modern
analytics machine
learning
for the next insur
era
fore
for
the
accept
kindness
for
for what a great sharing
thank you so much Mr dman and could you
please remain on stage uh to present the
flower to our sponsor could you please
remain ladies and gentlemen at penti
show we always encourage gratitude
culture and with sincere thanks from our
captain we would like to invite
representative of the co sponsor to the
states to receive appreciation flowers
from penal
Vietnam please welcome on the stage Mr
inun representative of
the go sponsor of this year event we
would like to invite to the state Dr D
Neer representative of jenry go sponsor
we would like to invite Mr basan iraia
representative of Pacific liary W
sponsor would like to invite to to stay
Mr T TR representative of Spar super
sponsor please welcome on the state Mr s
s k representative of s OA the silver
sponsor and we also would like to invite
Mr Len yuk representative of Munich re
super sponsor we would like to welcome
Mr CEO of presential Vietnam and Miss C
officer of presential Vietnam to go the
states and present appreciation flowers
to representative of the core
[Applause]
sponsors
[Music]
once again please join us to give a big
round of applause our great sponsor
event today thank
you thank you so much once again our
sponsor thank you m fman and Miss dman
thank
you ladies and gentlemen customers
centricity is the essense of Str stry
for us to become trusted insur
Enterprises it entails that we
continually enhance our service quality
to fulfill our customer needs and
expectation particularly in The Changing
Times the previous year has caused many
fluctuation and difficulties to the
economy the society and insurance
industry how can we as actuaries and
Industry participants cope with this
changes and satisfies our customer needs
now let us listen to two experts from
RGA International
reinsurance who will impart their
knowledge on the topic actuaries and
industries Ro in answering customer
needs we are honored to welcome Mr
alberter CD executive director business
development of sou ASO
market and we like to welcome Mr medali
the manager of business development of
South Asia markets please welcome on the
[Music]
stage that's that's
that's morning everyone uh and thank you
very very happy to be here so my name is
Albert and my colleague M for the next
25 minutes uh we'll be sharing with you
on uh actuaries and Industry roles in
answering customer
needs so let's start with something
light right you know how um iPad uh was
first you know very famous and obviously
are very common now and guess what it
wasn't invested by job it was actually
first being introduced by gates in the
year 2000 now I could see a little bit
of puzzle look uh around the room and
that sort of proved the point that
actually yep it didn't take off really
when it was first introduced even though
gates at that time
predicted that tablet will be the future
right and what happened is really the
product isn't really what the customers
was looking for it was still using
Styers gate was thinking about placing a
PC into a tablet so really the key here
is it is very important to consider
product customers
fit now I to be a little contrarian and
change uh the flow a little bit right so
I'll I'll start with the nend first
right this is the summary of our
presentation so if there is any free key
takea away from today is really
customers first customer centricity it
forms the key Foundation to solution the
product fit customer challenge in
Vietnam and today we'll talk about three
different customer segment and how their
needs and products will vary we'll talk
about the healthy the substandard and
the elderly segment and obviously all of
us in this room the industries right the
actuaries we all have contribution to
play and we'll share a little bit about
what uh we have seen across in other
markets
oops all right so let me kick off with
some early indicators I think um this is
really a chart showing a new business in
Vietnam's uh as you could see there's a
very nice trajectory from the year 2018
to
2022 uh early of 2023 there's about 40%
deep uh in the new business and really
to us it is an early indicator in fact
it's probably a clear indicator there is
a challenge with insurance product fit
in Vietnam
markets and really there are many
potential causes we can think about it
from the product design uh the the level
of complexity and we can also think
about it whether or not the uh
segmentation has been done correctly
distribution obviously does uh plays an
important role and and many other
operational challenges as well regarding
the economic development of the
countries now in short there are
multiple factors contributing and it's
not actually easy to solve this now what
we believe in RGA is that we all have to
put the customers at the center of this
solution if we want to solution this
customer should be right at the center
and it is the value that we believe and
we breath in in RGA so we place client
needs at the central of everything that
we do as an
organization so for today I will
introducing this concept something easy
to remember we call it the ice work of
insurance need but maybe before I start
this uh concept uh I I'll just like to
see show ofan who actually uh can
recognize the picture anyone can
recognize the picture okay I see some
show of hand so that is actually a
Titanic right
so why did Titanic think they could
escape the iceberg so if you read a
little bit of a story uh the the Sheep
actually thought they could escape the
iceberg right but why do they think they
could escape the
iceberg and the answer is really they
ignore the fact that the iceberg are
usually 20 to 30% wider
underneath so they thought they could
skip it and yet they didn't realize it's
a lot deeper than that and it's a lot
wider than that and to us that's a
perfect metaphor for insurance right
often when we think about insur our
insurance customer majority of them are
actually unaware
of their protection needs so just like
the iceberg the 10% is what they are
aware right so ask them about medical
coverage they say yep yep I will need it
right I I know I can see you know it's
very important medical has been uh
decreasing uh has been increasing in
term of cost but what often they are
unaware is the deeper end of the
iceberg right think about critical
illness who here thinks that critical
illness to pay medical is to is to be
used to be pay Medical
bills right and if you do think that way
it's
not right so what happen when you
undergo critical illness right often
think about who's going to have to pay
for that school fees think about who's
going to pay for medical expenses so the
need of critical illness is actually
also about income replacement it isn't
just about recovering for the medical uh
bills of
treatment and going deeper if you ask
any want any Young Folks uh in the room
here so who really need term coverage
probably none right I'm still healthy
why do I need and even if I pass away
who do you who actually will receive the
benefits right now um just to share a
little personal story and kind of use it
to highlight that the one that is really
going to say they need it is the one
that unfortunately really pass away
right so I do have a relative a contact
of hours 30 5y old you know very healthy
you know good you know job and and
beautiful house beautiful family and
then stroke
happens he passed
away without insurance coverage and it's
a very sad story because at the end of
it the dependent she really has to sell
the
house just to make admits so actually we
do have a real contribution there is a
real need to offer the death C
so going down a little bit deeper into
disability coverage don't even think
about it because no one really have
perception why do I you know I can't
even imagine being in the um a
wheelchair right so don't even think
about disability so in
short we're trying to paint a story that
most of the our individual customers
they probably aware at the top but
there's a lot deeper items of protection
needs that they may not be aware and
this is the opportunity for all of us to
actually think about how to solution for
this different
segment the way we think at it is we can
broadly divide the customers into three
broad categories of course everyone can
slice and dice but just for today we'll
try to simplify into three different
segment the healthy segment but it's a
segment we'll also call it the
vulnerable these are the folks that even
that often only aware at the top but
without realizing there's a lot of needs
underneath the iceberg the substandard
segment these are the folks that aware
but often they are constrained in terms
of purchasing insurance cover and the
elderly segment these are the folks that
probably very aware of the needs and yet
it's too late they're unprepared right
so for the next I guess uh remaining of
presentation I'll pass over to my
colleague Mii to further explore how the
three different segment have a varing
different needs uh of the customer of
the insurance needs
thanks yeah sorry um so hi good morning
so without further Ado let's get started
with uh the first segment that we are
going to talk about today the healthy
segment so for this segment nothing
necessarily surprising it's actually the
target market for most insurers and
that's the the market that they are used
to sell insurance product to uh I like
to believe that of this group still
although I'm increasingly getting uh
chubbier I guess over time and less
likely to buy like standard insurance
coverage but the key uh point about this
group although we know this group very
well is the fact that they have low
available Financial Resources okay and
uh maybe just to talk about my
experience personally um in the past
when I was um slightly younger just
started working um my priorities were
not necessarily insurance or buying
Insurance in general know it was pretty
much uh buying the new iPhone or or or
going on traveling I had very different
priorities and then the family family
comes and we want to buy properties and
and again the priorities are not
necessarily
Insurance um what have happen eventually
is that I had health care and then then
I run to buy insurance hopefully I could
get U covered yet but the that's really
the challenge when it comes to the
healthy people and they're quite exposed
in terms of resilience when you think
about it because when the worst happen
such as a c that was not uh we cannot
anticipate or or the pandemic right um
then they end up in a situation where
depending on the number of dependent
they have they might miss the coverage
that the family needs for for the
support right so of course it has to be
taken into account with the level of
financial literacy um those individuals
have I'm pretty sure that everyone in
the room would probably uh buy insurance
but that's not NE say the case about
most uh population that's not the
Natural Choice so actually we look at uh
some uh survey uh from from RG that we
call the voice of customer um that's a
survey that we do in order to make sure
the product we bring to insurance
companies make sense uh for the End
customer and one of the question we ask
as part of this survey is do you have
sufficient coverage for critical illness
medical expenses unsurprisingly the
result of the survey was very clear when
people are below 40 years old More than
70% of them they think they are fine
they have enough coverage but then when
they reach uh this 40 to 50 years old
the certainty and the confidence they
have start dropping um life even they
see their friends their families going
through different health challenges and
they start realizing that maybe I need
slightly more coverage than than what I
have today so it leads uh basically to
the point that um indeed you younger
individuals they don't necess realize
the need for insurance and as they get
older and have an increased risk of
being substandard they start realizing
the key issue and that's what we see
with the subst segment slightly older 35
to 55 and they are really challenged
when it comes to get getting insurance
they start having chronic conditions
that make Insurance more expensive for
them as well as having limited options
in terms of of what they can find in the
market um of course in terms of
resilience um that's not great um if
there is any particular event and I
think covid-19 is a very good example of
that and we are going to see some
statistics uh later but they are the
more more exposed and um they didn't
plan for it and their families might not
have the support they they need
eventually so of course they start
realizing uh the need for insurance but
start getting expensive overall
so what covid-19 has exemplified is the
fact that um such thing as obesity being
overweight can lead to three times more
chances to end up with a severe case of
covid-19 and looking at other chronic
conditions um that very common for
subtended uh such as hypertension the
number can be 2.5 times higher uh than
the general
population um in terms of segment the
last one we want to talk about today is
actually the elderly segment um segment
very close to my heart personally um
because of of of the my parents they are
very likely to have chronic illnesses
diabetes high cholesterol high blood
pressure um so they're the most exposed
in terms of pandemic risk that's for
sure um but also they have very limited
courage and they might end up like being
retired and not having the group
insurance medical courage they had in
the past so in terms of awareness that's
the opposite of uh the healthy segment
um they can see the 90% below the water
if we are looking at the iceberg they
can see all the problems they might
ignore the long-term care but that's
really a group that is generally
unprepared and highly aware of the
importance of insurance yet not having
Solutions offered to them um but there
is one key point about the retirees and
and and the pre-retirees they want to
remain self-sufficient they want to
remain independent as long as possible
there a couple of reasons could be that
they have been working hard all their
life to set their children in in life
and they want to make sure they are not
fincial burden for their parents or or
burden in in general so that's something
that we saw again in the voice of
customers uh the RGA voice of custom
customers and one of the question we ask
is um what are the current Insurance
solution um you are using in order to
cover your medical expenses so just to
bridge a gap because the survey has been
done with a group of respondent in
Singapore um that's typically your our
Universal Health Care that they have
been using uh uh and as well as Group
Medical and Medici Shield so then
because we were trying to understand uh
what is happening with the retirees we
asked them a key question uh what is the
impact of losing the group coverage when
you retire and more than 80% of them 85%
of them actually say that it has an
impact on them leaving them to worry
about um their ability to pay their
medical bills so another point that we
wanted to share that I find very
interesting is actually the fact that
the top concern for the retirees is not
your typical cancer heart attack and
stroke that you will see with a younger
population and the number one point that
they mention is the loss of ability to
look after themselves and that's a very
important point they know that they
might end up having cancer they know
they might end up having a stroke and
heart attack because we all die from
something eventually but for them what
is important is how can I remember
independent all my life okay uh the
other point of course beside the keeping
the independence is keeping their
financial Independence and and being
able to pay the medical bills and one of
the top concern as well is the
uncertainty about the medical bills and
how much they will end up like paying So
after talking about all those points um
that's the basics we intuitively know
about it let me um maybe ask one
question what can actores and life
insurance do in in order to help bridge
the protection gap for each segment and
and have a tailored approach so I'm not
here to give the one particular product
for each segment uh at the end of the
day we have to tailor the solutions to
the need of the customers and let me
give some spectrum of uh solutions from
neighboring Asian countries as well as
some example from from Vietnam for each
particular segment so the number one
point which is really important is
education the reason why education is
important is because as I mentioned
healthy segments insurance is not the
priority but we have to make sure that
they buy insurance as soon as possible
and before the health deteriorate it
requires an effort from all the
different uh participant in the chain of
value and from insurance government as
well as re Insurance to provide this
awareness uh to them the second point is
actually the strength of factu is
product and pricing so it's looks
evident when you think about it but it's
more challenging that what we might
thinking designing solutions that make
sense to them it's really this tailoring
uh event trying to understand the
healthy the young ones and the patterns
when they buy insurance and we need the
discipline to look into it uh very
frequently the need the need might be
changing over time um I remember like
maybe 10 or 15 years ago everything was
about the typical late stage critical
illness right then early CI came in and
recently we have been seeing some catcho
with ICU coverage the importance is
trying to understand those changing
needs over time and readapt this product
to make sure that they remain relevant
to the customers and they still make
sense for them okay in terms of um
National scheme um Vietnam has a very
good Universal like healthcare framework
uh so that's that's a good point and we
also have other opportunities from other
countries such as Singapore that provide
DPS uh which is some basic life and CPD
coverage to make sure that the lower
income still have some form of of death
coverage if the wor happen so now
looking at the segment that are would
say are slightly undercovered in general
um again education is really important
we want to make sure that even when they
are substandard they understand the need
to manage The Chronic conditions so
there is still like some part of
education and that's something that is
uh relevant for any age we never stop
stop learning in a way
but then in terms of product and
appetite it at this point that we need
to start looking at design tailed
solutions for the customers so in order
to address that of course we have a
couple of example of diabetic product
and and I think in in Vietnam there was
in
2019 diabetic product that was launched
and actually RG supported um but there
also other solutions for other countries
and and the idea is actually to reverse
engineer here instead of pushing uh any
product that we work to for the healthy
segment to the substandard segment so in
order to address the way it can be done
uh I'm going to talk about uh the
elderly at the same time and the product
and appetite here and it's looking at
what is not working for uh the
distribution why they cannot sell a
product to the elderly what is happening
in terms of underwriting what are the
Huddle they are facing so this required
um a tailored approach that iners and
reachers can work together in order to
design solution that Target and we have
seen some example in other markets with
uh cancer product that were designed for
the elderly as old as uh up to 75 years
old for entry age and still remain
affordable for them which is the key
point because Insurance start getting
expensive when they're older so it's
about targeting the amount that they are
able to pay at the end of the day so in
terms of national SK
again uh for the older population I'm
just going to U talk about some
initiative because when life expectancy
start increasing uh it puts pressure on
on the population so that's why um there
are some countries uh especially with a
long longevity over 80 years old they
start offering long-term care product uh
as a base coverage as well so on those
words uh I'm going to pass it back to
Albert who is going to share like the
approach uh to
tackle
it thanks many and of course just the
last spectrum of solution which
obviously all of us here in the room as
an actress we do have that tools right
we do have this item which we are very
familiar and has been successful which
is actual control Cycles right so
basically defining designing and
monitoring the impact now it all started
with the recognition that customer
should be at the center of
it right and it started with the
recognition that there's no such as one
fit solution as you have seen that each
different segment of customers do have a
different level of Iceberg of what they
think they needs and the level of
appreciation they have and this is where
I would you know urge all of us in this
room the actu right to and also the
industry practitioner to think together
Define this problem statement together
and design the solution and do not
forget to always monitor it and provide
the continuous feedback loop
now with that I just like to touch uh
the very first three things that I sort
of described just to kind of recap and
and wrap up really client centricity is
going to be the key Foundation if we
want to solve the challenge in the
product fit uh of customers in Vietnam
markets right and you have seen how the
three different segment of customers do
have a very different Iceberg of
insurance needs so they're healthy the
substandard and the elderly and of
course all of us here in the room as the
players as the industries uh we all have
a contributing part and you know
hopefully we'll then bring in a more
sustainable a more meaningful insurance
solution in Vietnam for the next era
thank you very
[Applause]
much all right thank you so much Mr
Amber SI and Mr
medali uh uh all right so now we are
feel free to uh invite everyone if you
have any query or any question or
information need to be explained uh
please feel free to uh raise your hand
and our speaker can uh provide you the
answer and
information is there any questions from
our attendees related to this
topic
all right um okay please get the
microphone to
uh our representative please thank you
hi so I'm now from a Vietnam um Vietnam
is quite different in term of the
penetration we still have a huge 90% of
Market there so probably we don't have
to go in nich market like that but umu
one question is
um traditionally insurance company or
Insurance try to segment customer
different risk you talk about healthy
and subst
standard in the new world is there any
way that you know we cover insurance for
everyone because that's a go back to the
basic of insurance is the pool of risk
control right so everyone should be able
to join Insurance uh regardless their
sat and they share the risk among the
hell and the unhealthy population but
traditionally I always see that we
always try to have different segment and
different charge uh but how you think
about this future uh I see some uh China
Company do this kind of you know they
pull on together if you can do that it's
really a new game for insurance in
Vietnam or everyone can Joy the
insurance is right than Go by different
segment and
risk so thank you for for the question
um maybe to answera we share some
experiences we had in in different
markets right and why we were talking
about the segmentation uh
specifically um what we realize um
through our experiences is the fact that
when you go um to the distribution and
and they try to sell an insurance
product they sometimes are the one that
end up not pushing products to the older
segment or or people who are imped right
they are substandard
the reason why and I'm just going to
share an experience a personal
experience I had um my father-in-law uh
was seeking insurance coverage and he
went to the agent um so I was there and
he was explaining listen um I want some
death coverage uh in case something
happens and he start sharing about his
own uh Health
right at this particular point the agent
start
like I'm not sure whether you are
suitable customer for for for protection
so let me maybe um offer you some saving
products and if something happens later
on uh the money will go to your family
but that's not what it was looking for
so the way we have been working on those
issues um with at RGA is actually
looking at those challenges right in the
eyes and say okay how can we offer
something that works um for the
customers and the distribution in the
agent and the key was actually giving
the confidence to the distribution to
push the product to the customer but in
order to do that we have to work on what
are those challenges what are the common
conditions that those people and then
reverse engineer and work on solutions
that will remain relevant to the
customer provide them the protection
they are looking for as well as
remaining affordable because there is no
point pushing a product if the person is
not able to afford it at the end of the
day a standard uh prod ction product
that is offered CI might end up being
two times or more than the initial
premium right so at least that's that's
One Vision on how to uh answering uh
these different segment and those
needs thanks maybe I just add on a
little bit um addressing your point
around doing customer segmentation it's
something that we have always done I
like to put it the other way around we
shouldn't be seeing High per uh low
persistency if that's the case imagine
you buy a phone you really love this
phone you're going to stay on using it
so I think it's the time right to really
reflect
honestly is it really
fit when we say that we know do we
really
know when we say we pretty sure
attaching ILP with you know CI Riders
hospital car is going to be great is
that really true
do the customer really know so I think
we kind of like to just bring it to the
very
basic because the hypothesis and this is
really just within you know uh within RG
the hypothesis is that if the customers
knows the importance and we do see a
real societal benefit of having an
insurance a real benefit and
unfortunately the one that is going to
benefit is those that have heart attack
those that have chronic illness they
they will come out and say hey I'm very
thankful I have this insurance cover
right so bringing it to the basic if if
if that is really something that we have
done well and something that the
customer is aware the hypothesis is that
they'll stick right so I think that's
probably the first part uh really try
trying to uh kind of reflect and bring
things to the basic and and be very very
honest if you really want to solve it we
got to be very honest of it now the
second part of your question is very
interesting I like the idea right which
is how can we make this Universal right
not
easy the reason why I said not easy I
think um
essentially you know uh we are stuck in
the dynamic of you need to be
commercially viable right ultimately all
of us here you know we we need to make
sure in addition to delivery the service
there is some meaningful commercial
return right now at the same time
managing portfolio with standard and
substandard it takes appetite that's
number one it takes very very uh a clear
sense of uh risk taking and maybe just
to share a little bit we have done some
form of GI upsell but of course it comes
with a certain framework it comes with
certain life of thinking right so if a
person already have medical
reimbursement we know their experience
we could do some control now but what
you're alluding to is bigger than that
actually what you're alluding to is what
if we open for all right what if we open
for everyone and so far as I well at
least from from our sort of point of
view the one that have managed
successfully doing that is
government and there is an element of
trying to mitigate the anti- selection
by compulsory coverage right and some
Market Indonesia has successfully done
that uh when they first entered
universal healthcare uh they believe in
covering every body even those who
cannot pay the premium the government
will subsidize right and that itself has
again with the having the insurance
actually it provide the safety net the
confidence to actually push this
individual to contribute to the economy
because now you know when I'm sick I'm
not worried there's something's covering
right now I am not seen that is being
done in commercial world right but it is
not impossible I think there is a room
potentially uh and if any place to
actually start that discussion is
probably here but I do I do like the
idea because it does really bring in the
uh the value in the in the big and and
meaningful way so you have the scale
impact of it thanks thank you for your
answer and hope our answers can address
our attendees concerns we still have a
many more session ahead of us so we will
have to popon answering your questions
for now any further curiosity and
interest regard um related to this topic
we will deliver those questions to our
expert afterward we highly appreciate
all the answers and sharing from RG
International reinsurance representative
Mr albertus SI and Mr medali may we
invite you to remain on the stage and we
would like to welcome Mr mashi Edo
appointed Act of brenal Vietnam
representative of organizer to present a
appreciation flower to our guest
speaker
uh highly move to the Center thank
you once again thank you so much Mr AR
sitiar and Mr medali for your great
information and your attendance today
and share with us so many youth SP
information thank you thank you so much
once again thank you
thank you so much Mr maso as well thank
you and now ladies and gentlemen before
moving on to the next B we are going to
have a 15minute break we invite you to
enjoy a tea break uh at the designated
area outside at the lobby thank you and
the event will recommend shortly in 15
minutes and please be SE in the state
area by then to F facilitate the timing
execution of the program we hope you
enjoy the pr great thank you for your
cooperation thank
you
[Music]
ladies and gentlemen we appreciate your
participation in the two break and we
hope that you now rear your energy and
so ready to join us for the next
exciting sessions resuming our morning
session SE we will now explore a trend a
popular Business Association model that
has ganed significant attention in
recent years ban curin despite his nasan
state in Vietnam ban curin is rapidly
involving and offering opportunity to
diversify distribution channels for the
insurance Market thereby contributing to
revenue growth for both parties stepping
into a new era where more than
technology like Ai and digital
transformation increasingly Prevail
basurin
2.0 present noticeable aspect to discuss
now let's explore the heart topic banka
shuran 2 po0 partnering for grow given
by a beautiful speaker from squid3 Miss
Alisia Innovation manager of fly and
health sou Asia region let's welcome on
the stage Miss Alysia
[Applause]
[Music]
hi good morning everyone I'm hope you
recharged from the tea break I also hope
you didn't eat too much such that you
will fall asleep in my presentation
today all right okay so I'm Alicia I'm
the Innovation manager for Vietnam in
CIS and today I'll be bringing to you
the topic of Bank Insurance 2.0 and
definitely this is a topic that you may
have already been hearing about in the
news for the last one year so I hope our
sharing today will really bring you some
sort of insights as well as how we move
on from
here so I'll start off here that
insurance as we all know is a product
that is sold and not bought so what this
means is that you know unlike other
things that we buy in our lives most of
the the time it is a one we are driven
by our own ones and we will actually
make that purchase but insurance on the
other hand is most of the time when
someone brings up that topic or that
product and we will actually have to
consider think about it before we
actually make that purchase so this
entire process and the you know the
drift the drive to buy insurance is also
called the propensity to buy and this is
something that is low not just only for
Insurance within the banker Channel but
Insurance sold through other agents as
well as other distribution Channel as
well so when Bank insurance as a term
and a concept emerged in 1980s it was
defined as you know selling insurance
through the banks and that concept
actually makes sense and is still
relevant
today a lot of our Bankers in Vietnam
they also understand the Synergy between
selling insurance at the bank as well as
the other bank services because the idea
makes sense essentially you're selling a
protection product to someone who is
also thinking of financial planning and
all this actually goes hand in hand
which is why even today based on the
survey that we have done at swiss3 just
early this year when we understand the
sentiments of the Vietnamese Community
towards Bank Assurance 88% of our
Bankers are still very interested and
they find that insurance product are
very attractive to sell this may be due
to different things such as the ability
to provide their customers with a very
holistic value proposition the
turnaround time in really servicing
their customers or even just
commissions but one thing we have found
through our research is that even though
the banks may be the very first point of
contact in introducing and selling an
insurance product to the to the
customers and alarming 72% of them
actually eventually turn to their agents
to buy these products
so to me this number is actually very
very alarming right and does this then
mean that there is just no further
growth or no further potential in the
bank insurance site or are there just
some other challenges that we actually
need to iron out and you know we can
actually still move ahead and continue
to grow this
space so of course I'll cut to the chase
as you already know my title is Bank
Insurance 2.0 we are partnering for
growth so definitely there is some
potential and this is where we want to
share with you more
today so Bank insurance is definitely
still a growing distribution Channel
then we actually ask consumers today who
are already buying from the banks and
again this this survey was done by swier
earlier this year amongst everything
that's ongoing 85% of the customers
actually still felt that they find their
Bankers that they have been engaging
with they thought that they are
trustworthy and they would actually
recommend them to their family and their
friends of course if we were to look
into the topic of whether they feel
pressured to buy insurance this is where
the measure is a lot lower only a third
of them actually thought that the
bankers are acting acting within um
acting in their interest and they
actually being
objective but again this score that we
see here is not just something that is
relevant in Vietnam or something that is
only relevant in the bank Insurance
because when we ask consumers the same
thing and to rate their agents even in
Vietnam as well as other parts of
Southeast Asia the same Trend also
emerged whereby people just don't feel
that the insurance distribution channel
is acting
objectively but if we were to put this
measure aside and we were to look at the
growth from here the consumers today
more than half of them who are already
buying from the banks are actually still
very open to buy from the banks in the
future in terms of insurance product and
this again is still amongst whatever is
ongoing so definitely there is still
that potential for growth but we must
not ignore that there are some
challenges that we have also identified
so in our research we definitely found a
lot of different Trends and information
um that we can actually address but for
today I would like to just bring to you
three key gaps and challenges that we
know that we can help to address further
the first is product relevance to
customer needs as well as Bank
Services the second is the financial
literacy of the of the Vietnamese
consumer segment the Education and
Training of the bankers as well as the
knowledge of the consumers
themselves and lastly it is the mismatch
in the preferences of underwriting
process at the bank
channel so the first
the first Gap we have identified here is
in terms of product relevance so product
relevance is actually a top concern and
a top need in both consumers as well as
the bankers the bankers themselves they
know that bank that insurance being sold
at the banks must actually be tied to
the bank services so that it gives them
the compelling story to actually even
bring up insurance as a topic and to
actually bring this up to
sell so the very first recorded Bank
Insurance product in the world is
actually a mortgage linked insurance
that is actually distributed through a
bank in Belgium when they were selling
loans and that concept made a lot of
sense which is why it is still very
relevant today and that is because when
someone is in the mental capacity to
actually take up a loan they also
thinking about the case whereby what if
something were to happen to them and
they are unable to pay off their loan
while they're actually building their
homes so that concept makes sense which
is why this particular aspect of
ensuring that a product ties in with the
bank service is one of the top concern
and one of the top feature that a
Bankers actually ask for when they want
to have an insurance product on the
bank's
shelves consumers themselves they are
also very needs driven so when they
actually buying Insurance product they
actually really need to know that this
is going to meet my needs but today
based on the research that we have
almost half of the Vietnam consumers
themselves felt that the products are
just not tailored to their needs but you
may be thinking a lot of the products
that we have now at the banks are also
products that we distribute in the
agency Channel with some slight twixs so
why is it that they're successful at the
agents but not at the banks and that is
because we often forget the mindset that
consumers have when they actually buying
insurance or when they're actually
looking for services at the bank unlike
speaking to an agent whereby it is very
purposeful and you know for sure that
I'm going to be buying insurance and
planning for my family and my future at
the banks most of the time I'm there to
either take up a loan open an account
and if you were to push an insurance
product at a point in time it just seems
odd so the mindset is just not there for
the consumers to feel that these
products are actually tailored to their
needs moreover a lot of the products
that we have today are actually very
actually designed to actually only meet
individual needs but not the other
family needs whereby consumers actually
do prioritize covering for their parents
and their children and even their spouse
so definitely these are some gaps that
we can address as
well the next challenge here is in terms
of financial literacy so despite all the
efforts by our various distribution
Channel whether it's the agents or the
banks they have actually been trying to
really educate and talk about insurance
more to Consumers but Financial literacy
still remain
low and we know this because based on
the research that we have 41% of the
customers actually felt that they don't
receive sufficient information or
education about the products when they
are interacting with the bank staff at
the point of
sale but surprisingly if you were to see
the next stat here 78% of the bankers
have actually reported that they felt
that they are investing a lot of time at
the at the start of the sales process
they feel that they are educating the
customers a lot they're actually doing a
lot of needs and fit analysis yet the
consumers themselves don't actually see
the results of this and this actually
points to the ineffectiveness of the
education process and perhaps Bankers
just don't have enough tools and
resources to really give the right story
to the consumers or educate them or it
may just be a wider systematic issue
whereby Financial Le is just low and
people don't understand the need for
insurance in their
lives which is why no matter how much
you try to educate a consumer on this
the success Fate on this is just
remaining
low the third Gap that we have also
identified in the market is in terms of
the mismatch in the preference of
underwriting so this statement at the
top here right simplify underwriting
it is not something that we have also
it's not something that's foreign to us
and a lot of times we also know that
simplified underwriting is preferred or
rather we think that it's preferred and
perhaps we are also partially right and
that's because as you can just see here
the bankers themselves actually prefer
to facilitate a simplified application
as well as underwriting process and
that's because when you look at full
underwriting a lot of times this also
have a lot of um complex terms a lot of
documentation and paper paperwork and
the bankers may not feel equipped enough
to help guide the customers through the
process
itself guarantee issurance offer on the
other hand is not as preferred even
though as as as it says you're literally
giving the um application form as a s as
a success to the consumers once they
apply for it but there are actually
limitations in both simplified as well
as guaranteed issuance offer so in the
case of a simplified underwriting we are
often Limited by the Su assur as well as
the protection coverage that we can
actually offer to our consumers on the
other hand for guaranteed issuance
offers while a customer may be accepted
eventually their claims may be declined
because of some other pre-existing
conditions and this is something that
the bankers do not want their customers
to
have but the consumers themselves are
actually very flexible in the various
underwriting methods when given the
chance to actually do a full health
declaration a lot of them are actually
very willing to do so in in exchange for
premium discount or even higher coverage
so simplified underwriting is not always
necessary and it really depends on the
mode of sale the type of product as well
as how you actually interact your
consumers but we definitely still want
to recognize the challenges that the
bankers have which is a simplified
process we want to also brid the Gap
that what the consumers want which is a
better offering higher product higher
coverage or discount and we want to
bridge this to by still ensuring that we
give them a very meaningful
offer so what I've just shed here are
the three gaps that we have summarized
based on our study and of course there
are still many other things that we have
found but I really hope that you just
brought through those three Gap areas
and challenges because today we also
like to share with you three other ways
whereby we can see how we can improve
the current situation and actually close
off this Gap the first is to design
products that are of relevance to needs
and customers that's for sure because
that's literally our very first
challenge in the market the second is to
simplify product selection as well as
the onboarding process using data and
the third is to leverage on behavioral
economics to create more real as well as
meaningful experience when the customers
are interacting at the
banks so creating products that are
relevant to the consumer needs
and the bank service actually kills two
birs with one Stones you achieve two
things the first is a very meaningful
proposition for your consumers and the
second is to help your Bankers close the
deal much more
easily with the breadth and the depth of
data that we have at the banks we can
actually create very accurate profiling
of the the various customer segments and
identify what are their what are their
needs as well as their gaps through this
we can then use those information
to design more tailored products for
them for example families who are
expecting children we identify them
through their Bank transactions and we
can actually Target them with very
tailored prenatal or family cover so
that they can plan even further in terms
of their family
planning tying in with bank services
this was something I have mentioned as
well and this is important because like
I said Bank Assurance the first product
was mortgage was a mortgage link um
Insurance product and that is still
something that's relevant today so what
else can we actually offer that we can
also leverage on the same
concept so how about boosting the
coverage of working adults those who are
opening bank accounts constantly set
crediting their salary through the banks
we can offer them boosters as well as a
income protection
plan those who are paying off their
school loans or their school fees we can
offer them savings plan or even a
disability income plan to plan for their
future
or how about a preferential offering for
your mass affluent customers who are
very loyal to the bank you want to keep
them there but you also want to give
them something that is
valuable tying in all this to the bank
services like I've also shared really
puts them in the right mindset to
actually make the decision and it also
helps your Bankers to be a lot more
comfortable in actually even bringing up
the product and bringing up the topic to
your consumers to introduce to
them lastly
it is also to simplify simplify does not
mean removing the features or the
benefits but instead we look at how we
simplify the presentation of the product
to ensure that it is relevant it is
using layman terms that is relatable to
your very daily
lives the next item that we can also
look into is to is to see how we can
actually simplify the selection as well
as the onboarding process using data so
like I've shared earlier the banks are
investing a lot of effort and time into
the education process the product
selection and needs analysis but the
consumers are not feeling it so we can
actually address this area in two
ways the first is to come up with
something called the predetermined
selection framework so leveraging on the
segmentation that I mentioned just the
slide earlier we know the gaps and the
needs of various profiles of customers
this particular pool of information can
also be provided to your Bankers so that
they have that information and the list
of consumers that they know they can
Target as well as introduce specific
products to them within this framework
we can also include a next's best offer
such as those who are un who may not be
eligible because of underwriting they
can then be offered something that they
know they we know for sure that they
will get accepted while they actually
still benefit from the
coverage the second area that we can
look at is data driven underwriting so
leveraging on data such as credit scores
or other form of information at a bank
we can actually use this as proxies to a
person's health so for example someone
who actually recently bought a new house
they also likely to be in a much
stronger financial position they will
need to have protection plan and they
also likely those who are able to be in
a very good physical health to think
much further into the future and hence
it shows us that their health status is
also in a much better condition compared
to others this is where we can actually
Target this group of people with a much
better offer or to actually simplify the
underwriting so that they don't have to
do a full lengthy declaration just to
get the
product these two approaches here
actually aims to reduce the friction for
the bankers to upsell the product so
this means that they know for sure what
the customers need they they do not
actually be they actually not burdened
by just the needs analysis whereby the
consumers felt this is not done well and
they are also more guaranteed of a
better acceptance rate in terms of the
underwriting process so this gives them
a lot more confidence in also bringing
up the product to the customers because
they know for sure they will be they
will actually be eligible for
it now on the on the same topic of
underwriting what we have today and what
is also preferred by the bankers is
simplified underwriting and what I have
here are sample questions I'm sorry it's
a bit small um but there are three
sample questions that we often see in
the market when we talk about simplified
underwriting so ID like you to take a
look at these three questions here and
ask yourself how many of you can
actually answer these questions
confidently and know for sure that I'm
not holding back any
information so at least for myself when
I look at question to
have you ever had two consecutive weeks
off due to sickness injury in the past
12 months immediately I'll be thinking
back oh no what about the fever that I
had a couple months ago is is it's a
sickness right or I I actually sprain my
I actually spray my leg just earlier
this year that's also an injury but if I
were to say yes to this then I'll be the
kind of a cover but that's so
insignificant unfortunately that's how
simplified underwriting actually works
it's either you give all no and risk
non-disclosure which you don't know or
any yes and you immediately get decline
of the policy
coverage so how can we make this process
this simplified underwriting process a
lot fairer to come up with a decision at
the point of sale and that's where we
can actually leverage on more automation
as well as something called reflexive
underwriting
questions
what this means here is that we look at
the current state of underwriting we
actually give we actually layer in
further clarifications so going back to
question two if I were to say yes to any
of this the next level of questions
would be asking what exactly were those
symptoms were they something one off
were they something acute and based on
all this other information that I
provide I will then be accepted or
declined accordingly or even loaded
accordingly
what this does it really balances the
expectation of both the bankers as well
as the consumers consumers who are more
willing to give information their needs
are met and they can actually get
coverage or even a higher or even a
higher level of coverage Bankers are Now
supported with the guidance that they
may not have and may not be able to give
their consumers when they're actually
facilitating a simplified or even a full
underwriting and the last thing I like
to share here today is how we use
Behavior economics to create more real
and meaningful
experiences so buying Insurance often
comes out with very good intentions even
as someone selling it you also have good
intentions but these may be understood
wrongly mainly because there's always
uncertainty buying insurance is complex
and sometimes there's just really a lack
of trust on whether you're working in my
interest or not or maybe there's just
too many options so for example someone
who is again planning for a family I
want to actually protect my family
members I have very good intentions on
that but I'm not actually willing to act
on it because I don't know whether the
product they are recommending me is good
or not and that's where we use
behavioral economics to look at the real
driver to buy the product in the first
place we can look at how we actually
smoothen the entire purchase process and
ensure that and reassure you that you're
actually making the right decision so
that you actually go through with the
purchase
intention okay so Bank Insurance
2.0 I think as you can see by now I'm
actually coming to the end of my
presentation it is not something that is
going to be revolutionary we're not
trying to change the entire industry and
that makes sense because Bank insurance
is a model that works it has been
working so far it has worked in other
markets but how is it that we can move
on from here to make it even
better that includes designing more
tailored and relevant
products how we simplify the product
selection and onboarding process at an
environment that is only very complex
such as the banks and how can we ensure
that customers will always have that
miningful experience and are not
pressured to buy or do anything that is
that they feel uncomfortable about and
that's what we want to do to partner for
growth with your consumers your bank
Partners as well as the insurance so
with that I come to the end of my
presentation thank
[Applause]
you thanks Miss Alisia for your
interesting speech or should you have
any concerns related to this speak kly
send it to the organizer and we will
send it to our expert afterward once
again we would like to thank you Miss
Elia a representative of squid Tre for
sharing with us today may we invite you
to remain on the stage and we good like
to welcome Miss da home chief officer of
presential Vietnam representative of
organizer to give appreciation flower to
our guest
speaker please give a big
Applause give a big thanks to Elia for
your great information today thank
you we also would like to thank Miss D
one Now ladies and gentlemen ESG stands
for environmental e social s and
governance G it is a set of standard
used to measure the sustainability of
and social impact of the company's busic
activities and today several major
Global economies are promoting ESG CR
criteria to enhance Environmental
Quality and social equilibrium non
Financial factors like ESG have a
significant financial implication as
investing in ESG principle means the
business is committed to sustainable
development to meet the objective of
growth and Market expansion companies
will need to adapt to this trend that's
also our discussion topic unlocking syst
understandable growth ESG application in
life insurance and please welcome our
panelist to the stage M CH ship
marketing officer from Financial Vietnam
[Music]
Assurance please welcome Miss Elena
quick head of Business Development South
Asia of RGA International
reinsurance and please welcome Dr D Neer
Regional director of
Genry and welcome meter even Lee head of
pricing life and health re sou Asia and
India of
Switz please welcome our panelist to the
stage and now the state is
yours thank you and I we would like to
uh leave the phone microphone to Mr Fong
your host
today
good morning uh everyone um I think for
the past few years we probably know uh
heard about ESG a lot and it becomes a
birw for uh for like you know in the
discussion of at strategic level uh and
also at at group
level unfortunately up until today I
think ESG is is still a BW it is not a
lot of actions that's following up with
that now I would like to refer to uh one
of a very good report that I got from
PWC called from ambition to impact uh
about ESG Readiness for
Vietnam so far uh Vietnamese government
has laid a very good governance
foundation for ESG uh for businesses to
develop in terms of social we have a
consumer protection law and in and this
year decree on personal data Protection
Law on Banking and finance institution
and labor code uh in 2019 for
environment we have a power development
plan pdp8 National strategy on climate
change to to um 2050 environment
Protection Law and guidelines and on
governance aspect we have a steering
committee on cop26 commitment the mof
guidelines on disclosure of information
and security Market including ESG uh
related law on investment this allowed
extension of investment project um still
using obsolete technology so we can't
say that we don't have enough framework
on the government side for ESG to um for
for business to start
you deploy the ESG uh into our our
operation however interesting enough
that majority of company does not
have um sufficient action on it for
instance only 24% have a clear govering
structure um 71% lack understanding of
data required for reporting and 70% have
none of very limited external reporting
on ESG now for for the very first
question I would like to ask Elina um
are you surprised by the data and have
you come across enough ESG topic or
discussion during the um in business
meeting and with
insurance thank you for um yes I think
you are right um you know there are
efforts done in ESG um space but is
there enough right um although yes some
companies May have a framework and a
clear three pillars and the actions
against three pillars typically we ask
ourselves why are some ESG more at front
and some not so much um could be because
who are you accountable for or why are
you doing it for right is it the
customers the end consumers the
investors that you're accountable for as
well if you're listed and so on and so
forth but I think as business you know
um contributing to the community
Community we have a big role to play and
a big responsibility to take it forward
it's not just a theme that comes and go
I mean it started with green what gold
green several decades ago those who yeah
belong to the same era as me um and then
it became what more green and then
pollution and now ESG which is a more
holistic view of being sustainable for a
future so maybe if we look at the
business development itself and in
Vietnam I think starting with here
actually many years ago um at RJ we also
started ESG or more of infusing the
social pillar into a product and that
was in
2019 um it was an inclusive product and
um I be very happy to say that you know
we supported and built that framework
for Vietnam is first at that time 2019
uh it was a diabetic product for um
customers who are already diabetic
patients um and it is conclusive and
promoting for them to get protection so
without the way we underwrite and
onboard them and price it reasonably um
such that it's too attractive for them
to take it on as protection they would
not be able to buy a critical illness
product and coverage yeah so for such
customers we learn that they are very
aware of the protection Gap they have
however they know they cannot buy so
that is immediately a gap they foresee
but they under
yeah so bring It Forward from 2019 to
today by the way that product was called
sweet care so I thank your AIA for
working with us then and more you know
recently in ESG element as well um of
supporting the family social structure
we have infused um a first in Market
family floater benefit in a sound life
medical reimbursement product um so
again that provides the family to have
and share in the limits of a product um
it's a a bit of a family pooling concept
so the market has put you in place a
couple of you know initiatives
addressing the social aspect but I think
a lot more can be done rather than you
know systemically one or two products
here and there um one element that I
still would call out that I feel is
largely underserved is the Aging segment
yeah so the seniors as we know aging
population itself can have a very strong
strain on our economy on the the family
social structures I think as Asians um
you know we we hold the family very true
to our heart they are very important and
key priority if any of our loved ones
are not well or need more support
immediately the family will feel it so
the Civil segment is definitely
something that you know is urgent I feel
it's an issue that we should be looking
into and helping the support more um and
allow me to share a bit more of insights
why silver segment um Vietnam as we
looked into it World Bank the is the
fastest aging Society taking only 20
years to turn from an aging population
to a aged um and that was from 2015 it
entered into aging and 2035 as agent
yeah so it measures by the percentage of
population that above age 65 so once you
go into more than 7% you're in the Aging
I think you go more than 15% you in
agent and how does that compare why is
it called faster because it Compares
with Japan we looked at it Japan we know
that you know Japan have a lot of Aging
population right um however it's even
faster because Japan takes 25 years to
go from aging to agent but Vietnam is at
20 and the US is 69 years and the one
that's very long is France 115 years to
get into agan so just some statistics to
call out why is this silver segment you
know something that we may want to start
looking and planning for it also at RJ
we were interested so in our client
seminar this year in Vietnam we did a
poll and we asked our participants which
is you guys right and and ask you know
who would you rank uh as in in order of
importance from your family so we had
the children the family um the spouse of
course but what ranked high of course is
the children but almost as equally high
is the parents and then lastly to our
surprise is a spouse so we're thinking
why is spouse not important um you know
but we realized that they said the
feedback was because spouse um they are
independent rather independent mostly
they may already have protection so very
aware again the parents are the one that
are not covered right so um just one
number to call out how massive this
opportunity is is 17 million to
summarize that 17 million is the number
of additional seniors Vietnam will have
by 2050 so that's a huge opportunity if
you're looking at what you business
plans will go into so I urge you know
the actores The Regulators um who can
influence the social pillar and in
supporting you know protection for the
silver seniors and Infused into the
business plans and this will definitely
go into supporting you know government's
plan to increase life insurance
penetration from 11% to 15% by 2025 and
18% by 2020 so we definitely look
forward to that I think there's a lot
more we can do as industry together
Thanks Elena um by the way can I have
another mic up here please um so you you
just mentioned the um a very interesting
Target from from government saying that
you know by 2025 we need to you know at
least penetrate 15% and 18% by 2030 and
it took us 20 years to get up to
11% so on average two years per one
extra percentage um of of penetration so
the next question I would like to ask um
to Dirk is is um so
since we still have a large uninsured
population how do we prioritize and what
group of customer should we put
first that's definitely a very good
question um I mean it depends on what is
important to you to focus so uh when we
look at the healthy life actually there
is a large group of uninsured people who
have not yet purchased insurance for for
several reasons and when we look at the
characteristics of these people we see
that they're typically coming from a
lower income group that they have less
education and they are struggling
actually with this onboarding process
where you have to answer 10 questions
which even an educated person typically
doesn't
understand so if we want to address to
do something for this group I think we
actually really have to look also as tax
incentives we may have to look at
government incentives to help them to to
purchase a products and something which
is very important is education so we
really have to explain to these people
that looking for coverage now is highly
important for them for the future and
actually that's also something which I
currently find very interesting about
this conference because the SE the the
seams which we just mentioned actually
have been there in the the previous
presentations as well not under the
heading ESG but when you listened to
this actually the same elements in the
end came up and therefore for me when we
are talking about um the healthy
uninsured group of people the onboarding
process is one of the key Ash issues
which we have to address because if you
go to a person who is already struggling
to pay for the premium and you have to
explain them actually how difficult is
to to to purchase this policy
it's not going to happen so we actually
have to find here good solutions to make
it possible so this is a large group
which you have but then on the other
hand you actually have a smaller group
of people with disabilities and not only
about the people with diabetics actually
diabetics are very often mentioned and
we have seen solutions for diabetics in
many markets whether it's Korea Taiwan
Vietnam South Africa it's the first
group people think of but there are many
other people with mental health um there
equally important and here we really
have to see they're actually highly
aware that there is actually a need um
because they need the cover but often
they cannot purchase this so here we
actually have the challenge how can we
design the products and how can we
design the underwriting processes in a
way to actually make it a sale and some
unfortunate nuances our experience is
that these products are hardly sold or
hardly purchased I think we should
better say um for various reasons um and
I think we still have the the challenge
as actores also and as insurance
companies to make it better accessible
for um for people out there with these
disabilities so I think I don't want to
prioritize what is in the end better it
also we have many insurance companies
operating in in these in this market and
I think every company in the end has to
see where is their specific focus and I
think that's also what makes our society
good everybody is good or better in a
certain field and can contribute better
to a certain
development thanks D um my yes
Ivan so I think okay uh maybe I can also
supplement on on this part is the how we
are able to do it in a better way by
sharing some of the example of other
country are doing I think to support
them to increase the penetration I agree
with C that the lower income groups with
someone we we need to focus but there's
always um a difficulty to reach those
people one is their affordability and
second is how you are able to reach them
or to make them to understand the
importance of insurance so in this point
the government will have a a a very
important role to play just to share
with you two example for example in in
Malaysia the government are doing a a
scheme with uh private insurer to
provide a critical illness and Hospital
Cash cover a very small cover for the
people uh the income group below the 40%
of the the population something like so
it cover quite a huge population and and
is also free for the for the consumer
and the role of the the insure company
there is they will help to man manage
the claims and also to monitor the
experience so that's what how the
government and the pivate insurer can
work together and also another example
is in Singapore so I think PSC they also
mentioned that Singapore actually they
got this called DPS a dependent
protection scheme it's a very lowc cost
insurance that uh promotes by the
government the Government tried to
bargain with the direct company to to
have a tender so that they can have
offer a very cheap rate cut through all
the distribution cost and then to offer
a very basic mortality cover to all the
citizens so that scheme actually
Singapore is around 5 to seven millions
of people but that scheme also cover 180
90% of their population so you can see
the importance of the government playing
this role in
here I would like to zoom in a little
bit on the silver um group um if like
majority of us here probably um uh like
heard enough on a media that Vietnam is
a very fast aging population we
currently still okay um in sort of like
in know the golden population pyramid
however um in probably in the next 15
years we will become a very very you
know we we ow before we get rich that's
the
title now that's the interest that we've
been doing a lot of awareness you know
campaign from penal side but I would
like to ask you um from your expertise
area what is the challenge in order to
provide protection for that kind of like
you know group and how the ACT Society
here need to be um prepped in terms of
like preparing for that Trend in in the
future I'll give that go I think similar
to what uh n was asking today right how
can we get there yeah so I think key
thing is you know with all the brain
power we have here really the actores
and Senior Management and Regulators um
I would say start from the basis of
affordability because we know this
segment if you are not just diabetes or
four Heights right your chronic
conditions um high blood pressure blood
sugar weight High BMI Etc so with all of
that in mind affordability has to make
sense to customer right because if you
do something that cannot sell then it's
not going to benefit anyone right so
affordability and underwriting so I
think those two key factors are very key
like really key in balancing it right so
underwriting you need to make it an ease
of onboarding so you need to have the re
mitigation or the questions that perhaps
can address and target for the
conditions that we know the End customer
needs and the affordability has to work
for both not just customer but the
Distributors because if the Distributors
like my colleague shared right the
journey oh no Mr customer you all I have
conditions I'm not going to cover you
too much of a hassle right and then he's
just going to push another savings
product so affordability and
underwriting um the the onboarding
process is crucial to make it successful
so I think just start thinking from
there and then pushing the boundaries
and having the risk appetite to do so is
it from a one company or is it a wider
you know societal approach that's
something to be considered as well if I
may build on this we are for the silver
products we are struggling with one big
problem when people are young they don't
purchase it when they are old many don't
qualify
so I think what we need to to to help
people to understand is that they need
to purchase this product when they're
young so then actually the underwriting
process can actually be very easy I mean
and in Korea there are a lot of dementia
products which actually have been sold
with very little underwriting um and de
Korea actually has also found solutions
to make it attractive also at an at an
older age so I think we really have to
to find solutions to make it possible to
understand and to purchase this product
at younger ages because when you wait
too long it will be too too late or it
may be too
late so question to Ivan now with that
trend is inevitable um and also uh a lot
of things is happening in the you know
environment in terms of like you know uh
the the the activity and the pollutions
and things how does that change the
pricing strategy and what kind of impact
that we should be
careful wow that that's the a a million
dollar questions uh asking how are we
able to project um the future rates
right so I just before I start the
details I just quote one uh comment from
wh so is comment that overall the
climate change is Project to have
substantial adverse impact on mortality
despite the action that we may take in
the future
future so it means in the past if if at
trainings we always use the historical
experience to project our future but
actually there are some elements may be
changing fundamentally that are
affecting our forecast there's a few key
Trend I can highlight here and and we
can also discuss as well talking about
climate change there's a three key Trend
we can we can look at the first um is
the the hit the history Str so climate
change we're talking about the the the
is more like you can also talk about the
global warming that the the Earth are
getting heated and how it will affect
our mortality in a c s way for example
the old people if they don't have a
proper cooling at home it can also
easily to track out higher
cardiovascular risk so it can increase
the mortality and also global warming
will will also create a more more
frequent uh pandemic event like flatting
or tunasi which can cause catastrophic
losses so that's the the key Trend one
the second key trend is global uh
climate change will also increase the
chance of the um of the infection
disease because the the the the carrier
of those infection disase are more
likely to to live or to spread to other
area where where it was used to not in
that
area actually maybe maybe covid is not
due to this kind of um uh global warming
or or but it is exactly showing how a
infection disease can impact our Liv so
that the second area the third area is
the uh the air pollutions so the the the
the climate change will also increase
the chance of uh uh Wildfire or other uh
or or also the the the industrialization
also have a more emission of the the air
pollutants which have direct impact of a
several disease for example the the lung
disease or or other uh respiratory
disease so all this we is slowly
changing so it's a question for us right
now that if we are observing in the past
we always seeing mortality Improvement
which is due to a medical advancement of
the Breakthrough of different uh
medicines and also improved uh lifestyle
but going forward this may be continuous
but at the same time we are also facing
the challenge of climate change there's
a question for us to right now that our
our rates are sustainable for the
Futures so it's it's a very important
question for all the atray
here so with all of those
um achievement or or or kpi that we
wanted to achieve um and and the the
trend of like you know um environmental
changes and also aging population what
other changes we need to be aware of or
prepare in terms of governance
um in order to meet those
demand U maybe I I I can try this one um
so I think ESG is a very holistic topic
we're talking about yeah pricing may be
one part of it the social responsibility
is another part how we can serve the the
the underserved market and more
importantly as a as a corporate we may
need to have a more clear strategy what
what we want to achieve at the end of
the date so it can it covered um our our
investment strategies and it may also
covered our our uh corporate strategy
now how to how internally we can reduce
the carbon uh uh production so kind of
kind of different things so it it so you
can you can you can also see what the
other country they are doing so it's
start from the government side so the
government will have a different
framework to to to try to encourage this
DG and then we'll go to the the Corp
side and how they can also uh
incorporate those framework so so it
start from the very Senior People the bo
of director need to aware of this and
then pass to the middle management how
they can execute it and then and then to
a to our working level how we are able
to reinforce all the measure that we are
talking so so as as maybe maybe as an
aty it looks a bit far from an angle but
in fact it will affect our day-to-day
work as well for example the management
framework how are we able to uh ensure
our compliance of of those guideline
from the government that's the important
part and also as I said the pricing part
of the future how we are able to address
the climate change impact that can be
another angle of looking into it and
also that you can see the lot of
government they are also promoting those
on top of the government they also
talking about the SC scenario testing or
stress testing how are we able to ensure
we have enough capital to cater those uh
unfortunate event or pandemic event so
those those are the the work that we are
going to see more and more coming to to
place in the market if the government
are very keen on this
topic you actually touch on a very
interesting aspect of ESG when we are
looking at ESG I think most people have
a good understanding what is e
environment
so redution of carbon emission and
everything when we talking about s
social everybody has a good
understanding yeah social we know what
what it is when we talking about G
governance many people draw a blank and
I have understanding for this because I
mean it it is a different concept um and
possibly most challenging to to follow
through so in our company actually
governance goes very much with code of
conduct so we have a very
detailed code of conduct which
stipulates what actually the company
expects from us as employees and in the
end our work as employees in the end
also contributes to the work which we
are doing and which we ultimately also
de deliver to our
clients I think definitely the
governance needs to come in um it's it's
all a part of a framework otherwise
you'll just be setting aims and goals
but not really acting on it right so
governance is important to ensure that
the cycle is complete and then to have
actually the ethics B to actually have
the steering committees um for the
different pillars to actually see those
through yeah and and putting that as
part of your either your company
scorecard your kpis down to the
employees themselves for example social
you know within our corporate companies
Dei how do you implement that how do you
compensate individuals for that as well
right so it needs to really flow through
and go down to everyone so that it can
be an effective ESG strategy yeah thank
you so so in order for um ESG is no
longer a buzz word but actually be put
in practice what advice or
recommendation uh from each of you to
the um actuary Society here um so that
we can start you know for for next year
we will proudly have some achievement to
share instead of just talking about the
buz
word okay I'll
go um I mean we we ourselves as life
insurance even when I started looking at
this topic I said well we just I feel
like we are in the back burner of it we
only certain pillars but when we think
further and we think of how large life
insures are and how large of the amount
of you know Capital reserves that we
hold and that we invest on behalf our
shareholders and policy holders and
customers we actually have a strong
mandate and a strong opportunity to send
you know the message to through our
investments through our action
because actually we are not on the back
burner we're at the front line of it is
what we do with our plans and what we do
with the monies that we actually are
safeguarding on behalf of policy holders
and shareholders yeah so I think there's
a lot more that can be done um I I also
want to share a bit more like other than
thinking of just social of of certain
things that we have seen in the market
sharing Beyond Vietnam let's say in
Singapore we have got great live that
came up with a product it's is a green
product it's a single premium endowment
but it says that the Investments is in
green Investments yeah um and then we've
got Hong Kong food Tong life where if a
customer buy a policy the company grows
a plant so plant a yeah grow a plant for
buying a policy so the company um
commits itself to do that yeah so so
things are you know there are lot of
Inspirations around you know very
neighboring countries no need look too
far they are feasible is whether do we
put it in our plans and we do we think
enough of it we know in our execution
yeah of our business planning
yeah actores are trained to analyze
problems and to to um project future
cash flows into the future um to look at
the solcy of companies uh to do risk
management I'm convin we are doing this
very good and very well but we are also
trained to come up with solutions to
look for Solutions and to address
problems and um I would actually
challenge ourselves a little bit I mean
I earlier heard this question what about
universal health insurance I mean when
we are actually selling a health
insurance policy there is a certain
group of people who don't pass the
underwriting process now we can actually
argue okay that's a small group of
people but actually they are not so
small and they are also important for
the society
and this small group of people also can
make a lot of noise which actually can
have a negative impact for the insurance
industry overall so just an idea so what
if we challenge actually ourselves and
we try actually to find a solution to
make actually also for people who have
to be declined in such an underwriting
process to find a solution so this could
for example be a um an approach to say
okay we actually have have a basic
health insurance policy so then actually
yes everybody knows that if I sell a
health insurance policy and I ensure
people who are very sick I will make a
loss so therefore having the policy
itself will not be the solution so but
then we can put a pooling process on top
where actually the certain negative
experiences will be pulled among all the
life insurance companies so I think we
have to make it bigger not only talk
about in the in the context of our own
insurance company but for the industry
how can the industry find a solution and
I believe that actually actes are well
suited to make corresponding Solutions
and to come up with the proposals yes we
certainly will also eventually need the
support of the regulator and the
government I think the initiative can
come from our
side yeah I I will also similar along
along that line that um we are insurance
company and also Insurance coming
actually we are big cooperation so
actually we should have our social
responsibility here so of course we need
to answer to our
shareholder that uh deliver uh profit
deliver newb newb value inforce Valu are
important of our kpi but at the same
time don't forget we are also part of
the society when we take we need to we
hopefully we can also give back
something so just take the example of
the the Malaysian case I mention
actually that that direct company the
Govern government are helping to to do
the promotion or or or to do the the
scheme but actually the funding money of
from the direct that direct company is
showing that they are they are willing
to to sacrifice some of their margins
for the good of the society so it can be
also a way that uh as an aty I think we
have a much value added here that we can
if we are allowed to have several buffer
of several money to to design a product
for those um people they are not able to
afford the insurance or those um have
other issue not be able to buy the
insurance then we can see what is the
best use of that money on one hand we
can find the solutions of it on the
other hand we can also do a bit more
calculation how to mitigate the risk so
it can help to uh optimize the the the
money that we we may have so it's also a
very important we can think about our
social
responsibility thank you panelist um I
think we cover all three aspect of ESG
um just now so now the floor is open for
the audience um who wants to have
question to any any of us here um Can
can please
raise or if you are too shy then you can
just send it by notes and then we can
respond it
later um I guess that's about it um so
um thank you very much um Elena Durk and
Ivan for sharing your valuable um
insight and and experience um so that we
know hopefully that this time next year
uh when we get together we have um some
tangible evidence on ESG uh development
um to share among the um actually
Society here once again thank you very
much thank you very much you thank you
thank
[Applause]
you so thank you so much Mr Jan Fong for
your great horse today and we also would
like to thank our panel we are so
grateful to learn the expert inyon
perspective and practical sharing thank
you so much please give them a big round
of applause for the great information
today thank
you so our beloved attendees our morning
sections has come to a close and we will
resume our afternoon agenda at
1:30 would like to repeat 1:30 p.m. and
we kindly ask for your present before
1:30 p.m. to take your seat once again
we appreciate your punity to ensure the
event smooth flow thank you and now
please enjoy your lunch and we will see
you at 1:30 p.m. in this B room thank
you
members of prudence of Vietnam for such
a delightful performance that added a
vibrancy to our conference atmosphere
this afternoon and those was early
Christmas gift from Prudential Vietnam
to celebrate the approaching fasted
Christmas spirit and gling exer of
Peaceful Christmas filled with joy
alongside our dear rich ones and please
enjoy our gifts all right so now ladies
and gentlemen are you ready for our
session this afternoon afternoon um
Opening Our afternoon agenda is a very
special guest this woman is a world
champion Trail Runner called the trail
queen of Vietnam and having outstanding
achievements in local and Global Trail
and onra trail races some of which
include in September of
20122 see have overall winner Vietnam
Mountain Marathon one 100 kilom category
and in the December of 2022 female
winner UTMB do inan 50 kilom category in
Thailand and female winner Asia Trail
Master Championship 75 kilomet category
in Philippines and in April of
2023 female winner xtera Asia Pacific
Championship 35 kilom category in Taiwan
and in May 2023 female winner UTMB
Australia 50 kilom category and in
September of this year for poison UTMB
CCC in chamonic France can you guess the
names of who is free who is fre can you
guess then let's all look at the stage
and God did Vis and gain a better
understanding of our special guest
profession
athlet please watch the
[Music]
video
for foreign
[Music]
foreign
foree
[Music]
about 30 years ago in the north of
Vietnam in the village of Bon a runner
was
born game game game oh run run run I'm
tired I want to R I know Hai but to be
one of the best trail Runners of the
world there are no shortcuts only hard
work and
discipline hello my
name I'm professional Trail runner from
Vietnam z e gim he my head
coach thank you
hope there are many Trail runners in
this room can you raise your
hand I see
one okay uh maybe that many of you
doesn't know what is trail running trail
running means running through the
mountains okay this little gu here how
she runs through the mountains there are
different distance 15 50 75 100 160 kilm
which is 100 miles there are many
different distance in the trail running
the scene but ho as many Vietnamese
didn't start running she start going by
bicycle when she was a kid she used to
go to school by bicycle as many of
Vietnamese do but it was not until she
was 16 or 17 that she discovered running
and it discovered at the high school
when she joined a competition and she
fall in love so then she decided to
study to be a sports teacher and she did
exams but she didn't pass how did that
happen uh there one one 1 M 55 but me
only 1 M
53 then I don't go to university I just
go to sap toy job so she was left with
no opportunity to go to university move
to Sapa start working a little bit like
she runs crazy so she start doing many
jobs here and there in different
positions in Sapa different jobs
different opportunities and life goes on
and she get married but sadly a year
after she get a baby and she get
divorced and she was left as a single
mom alone in
Sapa uh it's what very hard for me to be
a single mom because in Vietnam people
don't understand the the single
mom and I'm busy I have a hard work and
I get fat very fat yeah and I I think
running will help me Lo the way not
right now so after two months of running
to lose weight she saw the bmm which is
the Vietnam Mountain Marathon one of the
most or the most famous Trail marathon
in Vietnam that happen in Sapa Square
she used to work at the tourist office
she saw that race every year so two
month after she start running she
decided to join the 21 kilm trail
running race in
bmm uh from beginning I run crazy crazy
fast first time I run in 21k and run
crazy to the pH L and I win
over that mean men and woman then people
think I'm cheating because I'm from Sapa
and I know the RO very well but so how
show the GPS file they see that she was
not cheating so everybody was very
impressed although I even her friends
were very
impressed uh my friend told me I should
run some R in
Vietnam so she decided to jump from 21
to 70 km the second race so she next
race was in mocho the BTM and she joined
that race on a very very hot
day first time I run 75 I so excited to
that I run crazy uphill downhill
flat and until 55k I get crum in my leg
I cannot move I ch
work working working to the FED light
and still
win so that was very impressive
performance because she win she get the
victory first female happens all happens
it was a very hot day she still win by a
very long lead on that race so that
coached my attention I'm one of the
founders of mut Sports uh garments
company in Vietnam and I saw her
performance and I thought wow if she
managed to do that in that weather in
those conditions one of the hottest days
ever in mocho for that
race that girl definitely got something
so I contact her and I say look I saw
your performance you're very good would
you like some
sponsorship and I tell him I will answer
game in few day because I didn't know
what a
sponsorship what a m company I
everything him told me very new for me
so thanks God a week later she answered
yes and we start working so we sent her
some clothing some garments for her to
try but very soon I realized that it's
not just that she didn't know what it
was sponsorship or what it was my brand
it was that she barely know anything
about running or trail running she had
no idea who were the famous runners the
famous races what it's a workout what
it's a straa or a straa segment what
it's a heart rate monitor she barely has
any idea and we start working together
to beat by bit explaining her what was
running so next race we joined it was
the theat ultra race second 70 kilm race
in the
L uh that R very easy to me
but I get injury from 20K in my need but
I keep running easy to fin it and still
win so first of all as I said before um
first race 21 second race 70 third race
70 this is like in the movies or in the
tv ads yeah don't try this at home this
is not the way to to chase trail running
but so she got two injuries in two races
because she was also doing some Road
running racing at that moment and we
take some time it was also covid times
we took some time to cure the injuries
and then we start
fighting we start fighting because she
wanted to race the next race 160 kilomet
so 21 7070 and 160 and I say no next
race should be 100 and then we start 160
100 160 100 I finally convinced her and
the next race it was be pmm again the
racing Sapa this time for the first time
kilm uh I'm so excited for first time I
run in
Sapa but that that race start at
night and you know it's first time she's
running a 100 big participants big names
and after 10 kilomet she called me I say
gim I have a problem what happens say I
have a problem I have a problem I say I
I see you on the tracking and you're
okay say I have a problem I'm running
with the first mens I said yeah I know I
can see it I have a problem these mens
run very
slow and I say yeah but don't worry I
say can I go can I pass them I say no no
keep there they are professionals they
know what they are doing this is a very
long race you're only on 10 kilometers
take it easy keep
going I I listen to game and I keep
running until 40K ah I feel so sleepy
and tired so I let the foot man run
first until C before I got I stopped to
eat watermelon and that man are you here
yeah I say yes but let's go first I need
to eat watermelon so you go first and
that man go first and I after I eat
watermelon I keep running to the cp5 and
and I meet gim gim told me oh that man
third man not not so far from you I say
ah
interesting then I eat some nutrition
and I keep running until cp6 I see him
in front of me then I put her to leave
him he not happy yeah of course he not
happy then I pushing until the last clam
and I Con G so we're on the race few
hours I don't remember how many at the
end but and again she get get a phone
call and she called me in the middle of
the race say gim I just passed the first
man but he's not happy he look angry at
me why do I do I wait for him because he
looks angry I say what are you talking
about just keep running just keep keep
running
running and I listen to him I pushing
downhill crazy sometime I scare myself
because I down he crazy nice stor to the
fin life and I
win um over on again that mean men and
woman so people were in shock obviously
overall win again 100
kilm and then a journalist asked her
it's like okay this is your first Kil
100 kilm
race will you do it again and she
answer
um maybe not today um maybe
tomorrow so I don't know how many of you
well not many but have done ever a 100
kilm trail running race but it's hell
yeah and to ever consider to do it I
would say in a month that will be weird
but to even consider to do it on the
same day or tomorrow that was crazy give
us leave us all in shock so we were like
okay we got some serious here in hands
so I contact one of the best trail
specific running coaches in the world
professional nutritionist a professional
strength coach we set up a group called
push and smile coaching and we start
working to get ho into a higher level so
then we go to her first International
race UTMB do tanon in
Thailand for time I run outside Vietnam
I'm so excited to that from beginning I
I get shocked because there the runner
run super fast like from beginning
uphill downhill and flat I I control my
R very well too I always in the top one
until 42k I get crum in my
leg nobody can imagine that crme my
muscle run out of my leg my skin thir my
bone and I I cannot run I stand I cannot
stand I just sit and cry until the foot
man P me second man P me I say enough
that enough I need to stand up to climb
to the m to the top of mountain then I
try to climb to the Top Mountain and i d
now he crazy crazy I pushing to the to
the fied light and I win so another
Victory but no time to celebrate because
we had to get a plane fly to the
Philippines to theau to join the finals
of the Asia Trail Master championship in
the bow in monapo which is RA 70 kilom
there stars on the beach go to the top
of volcano and go down
again uh that right really really hard
for me
my leg doesn't work my body doesn't work
I cannot eat anything from beginning but
I keep pushing the f g she super super
good but I keep pushing until I arrive
to the top of mountain I see the the B
and I feel fresh after that I D you
crazy to the Finish night and still win
a
again she was not very happy obviously
two races 50 and 70 in one week which
actually not recommended but we had to
do it at that time uh it put her on a
spot at least in Southeast Asia
everybody start knowing here and then we
start planning the 2023 season to go
into International stages so we start
preparing
here we keep training we get the team
already start working work on nutrition
strength proper work plans next race we
did theat again she's still unbeaten to
date in Vietnam we went to uh Taiwan for
the Asia Pacific championships and to
Australia where we start encountering a
lot of problems with the visas it's not
easy to travel for Vietnamese people
less for Vietnamese people with minimum
resources economic resources although
she's a professional Trail Runner so we
struggle to get the Visas we get into
Australia last minute but managed to go
there we actually get the visa I think 1
hour before the plane correct yes but we
head into Sydney we race there we get
another Victory and there we came back
to Vietnam ready to join the next
chapter there is one goal for most of or
a main goal for many of Trail Runners
which is UTMB UTMB is the main race in
France in the Monon blank it turns to be
nowadays like the World Championships of
trail running so again start working
with the
visas
difficult difficult so difficult that we
didn't get the visa until one week she
flew to Spain everything was ready
everything was booked but we didn't know
if she would be able to come but finally
she arrived in Spain we're ready to go
to
zal raised by the Golden Trail series of
Solomon in Switz land 32
km uh first time I be in
Switzerland beautiful mountain the
mountain very big the bigger in Vietnam
and the we have been in the one Village
full of elite Runner they are
professional but um the organiz V and I
I have a m m one one the kilan zette
he's he's super famous in the trail
running and the organiz Very night they
perfect everything the land dinner and
uh and breakfast they invite um Elite
runner go to the top a mountain Heaven
land in there with the c car the the
race is very nice for us it was like a
little bit like I don't know like being
in Wimbledon or in Roland garos or the
austa Masters or or like a big event it
was the first time we were in such a
stage Runners were amazing just by the
look uh organization was fantastic the
teams look so professional and we were a
bit like septic of the performance also
because we were not trained for that
distance we were training for 100
kilometers later that month but anyway
the race it was very fast 10 km uphill
10 flat and 10 downhill
yeah and I get Crum from beginning I
just get Crum never in my life get Crum
downhill and but I don't didn't I keep
running to the ph and I finish the
number
26 and first time I not win so we were a
bit not shocked because it wasn't the
right distance and we know we were in a
bigest stage but as she say obviously
she always win and that day finished 26
but it was a very good lesson for us uh
it get us actually ready for our big
race which UTMB CCC 100 kilometers at
the end of August
and give us the peace I would say to
face that second race so we went back to
Spain we went to the Pines North of
Spain to train couple of weeks being
ready for the big trip to mon blang to
shamon for the CCC
UTMB first time I be in VIP car the
motor home car but
VIP I inside her everything like the
like the
house so yeah VIP VIP I'm not sure but
we rent one it was a big motor home uh
it was the first time actually that I
even ran one so we travel with my kids
with ho with another female Runner of
our team and we head to shamanix but we
arrived
there and everything was very confusing
um they were saying that some roads will
be closed that you could not Park here
you could not park there it was the
first time so we didn't know much and we
end up camping putting the motor home in
a camping and taking public bus to go
every day to shamoni to to visit but
that then it makes that we didn't see
the course uh we didn't practice that
race is 100 kilm again with 6,000 M of
elevation this is a lot of elevation so
anyway we did our best and we were ready
for the race
day I wake up very earlier in the
morning to take the Bir Go to start when
they AR right nobody there and when the
the race start I stand in front of many
Runner the elite runner in the war but
from beginning I control my my speed
very good I run very well I didn't know
I'm in the top one until I see fairy
fairy helicopter ah fa helicopter and
the TV ah that I know I'm in top one I
didn't know then that race it's
broadcasted in YouTube live uh over I
don't know well I guess all all the
countries in the world and people are
texting so they are texting me saying oh
did you see how is going first I say I'm
sure I see it because I'm here looking
for her but people were getting crazy
even the commentators on the screen they
didn't know who was she how it was that
possible where she was from but they
were saying okay it's only 20 kilm on
the
race let's see let's see what
happened I keep running until 25k do the
second gun she B
me but uh it's okay I think just
beginning no problem until 42k the third
gun she B me because I stopped to eat
orange but I need to eat I I show her
part me but I I I I let her run first
until cp5 I see
him I was so tired when how mention CP
cp5 C is checkpoint checkpoints are like
water stations yeah in in this Ultra r
places you have different checkpoints
where you can get some water or some
nutrition some of them also you can get
assistance so in checkpoint 5 she get
assistance I was there and calm her down
change her shoes change her socks ask
her to eat to eat more to eat properly
to relax she was doing very well she was
running forth in the biggest race in the
world for the first time without knowing
the course that was amazing and she kept
going yeah I my body very hurt my leg
hurt my feet her but I keep running to
the cp6 I meet gim again so she was
really tired she was I wouldn't say
pissed off but she was like I can't run
anymore I'm so tired I give her more
gels and I say okay keep going you're
doing great still forth keep going keep
going keep going but I left the
checkpoint going back to shamanix to the
Finish Line to wait for her and after a
few kilometers I saw her on the road
walking so I go to her next to her I say
what what what what happened what are
you doing say I'm very tired my legs
don't run I say but you know keep
pushing all Vietnam is following you
they are texting me crazy all your
coaches are encouraging you your son is
sending energy to you we are all there
just keep pushing at least try to do top
10 which will be an amazing result but
at least keep pushing a smile keep going
keep going but I don't worry about game
say because my body cannot run anymore
I'm so tired I get hurt everywhere I
have a run hour B Trey no energy to run
then the fet gun she arrive in the L
clam I try to run with her in L clam
until the last checkpoint she stopped to
eat that time down he crazy to the
finish line and I leave her I run crazy
like the rock fell from the
mountain nobody can imag that s after
that I D in the some point I met the
Valentine Valentine is the team me
running then he asked me what what what
what happened I say the fet gun behind
me no no time to stop I need to run I
need to put and he say who I say behind
one second and he he said let's run
together and we run together until the
2K from the fin life I see the the third
gun wow she run very slow because that
that road very technical full of rock
where dented the RO and I put her to
leave her but she put her to leave to
follow me too and I put her put heart
until the flat she she she put should
leave me and I cannot follow her anymore
because my body really really hurt I
cannot even she only I show her in front
of me I cannot I run out of energy and I
finish top four by 23 Second so after
100 kilm through the mountain 600 M of
of elevation 12 and 1 half hours she
finished four by 23 seconds
um that was amazing uh I see that you
not many Trail Runners here but this is
just absolutely crazy it's mental and
obviously the commentators everybody who
was there they could not believe it they
they were completely in shock uh first
time in that race without knowing the
course and leading or almost leading for
12 and a half hours so after we crossed
the Finish Line we had to pass the
dopping control they do dopping controls
in those races and everything was fine
she went to sleep I celebrate a little
bit but next morning she wake up and
first thing she
say uh gim I think I can win in z r with
11 hour 30 minutes but we are need to
change something so 1130 11 hours 30
minutes it will be like a course record
what it's amazing is that first thought
when she wake up next morning is already
thinking 2024 we're coming back we're
going to do it better and we're going to
try to
win this been an amazing journey
for three years I think yes three years
from almost not knowing anything to the
elite elite elite elite when we were
there we saw the other Runners we saw
the other teams that they were like F1
teams I mean they they get ready just to
give you an idea over all the check
points we lost or we spent uh 16
minutes in total the winner spent 9
Minutes the second spent 8 minutes the
third spent six minutes and we spent 16
and we end up fourth by 23 seconds so
for sure next year we can do it better
but how do we get all this how did we
arrive
here um we work very hard with a lot of
work we spend three years elbow to Elbow
uh learning many things from the very
start uh it's a very long way it's like
the trail running there's different
distance but in order to progress you
need to try to maintain your speed while
you're gaining mileage yeah don't start
the house from the roof it's like
working you don't finish or get
graduated in University start in a
company and be the director in a month
time yeah normally it takes few years
and that's what Ho's been doing the last
three
years I
yeah I'm I'm the single mom if I can do
that so you can do that too but I need
your help to find more sponsor to help
me next year in
2024 in 2024 we're planning to go to the
biggest races in the world we're
planning to
join podiums as much as we can but for
that yes we do need your help we do hope
that you can share how story she's on
Facebook as Howa Runner she's on
Instagram as how her Runner as well and
we hope you can share her story share
her dream to be one of the best trail
runners in the world uh because her help
your help is needed to be and to show
the rest of the world the power of
Vietnamese
athletes thank you thank you very
[Applause]
much all right thank you so much Miss
how and Mr gibo for your interesting
story and uh yeah it inspires a lot and
we think B of you like have a perfect
match together and we wish you all the
best for the next coming years 2024
right it's more and more sponsor and win
a lot of title all right also now we are
so ready to give the time for each and
every one of you in this Ballroom if you
have any question feel feel free to
raise your hand and uh as to our
representative Miss how and miss gibo
any
question who who want to joines the
racing with Miss
H any question L
gent any curiosity about the Journey of
MHO well I explain you first let's see
if we have any question um her next race
is in two weeks uh UTMB in do tanon
again in Thailand she will do the 100 km
again in two weeks and yeah for us
that's okay obviously I'm the coach I
know her very well but this is a little
bit like I think the title of this
conference no the next era uh ho is like
the really the next era on the trail
running I mean she started late but
she's ready mom she knows what's life
and when you will see and you can follow
the race live on YouTube in two weeks
you will see that from the start
line just
flying wonderful wonderful in two weeks
right in uh Thailand all right wish you
all the best in that's racing all right
so uh any
question all right so now uh may we
invite Miss how and Mr gimbo please
remain on State and we would like to
invite Mr maso representative of the
organizer to come to the state and give
the flower booket to miss hati and Mr
[Music]
gibbo an apologize to the travous effort
of our special guest
today everyone I
apologize yes and we wish you robot's
health and continue to harness your
enthusias energy to achieve even more
success thank you for your presence at
today's conference once again please
give a big round of applause to misso
and Mr gibo and we wish you all the best
thank you thank you so much thank you so
much Mr
M thank
you all right this is the first speech
of our afternoon and now uh we will have
a very attractive part part of this
afternoon but before that we just uh
kindly remind you that
um in the gift the small gift that the
Santa Claus uh gave to you uh at the
beginning of the event uh it's a cake
right bus it's not old inside the cake
we still have something we still have
like special message so could you please
open it break the cake and you get the
message thank
you all right all right and now before
we start with the Actuarial topics we
are going to have a mini game right now
so we will have so many attractive
vouchers to give to you that can be used
to replay cast and apply for over 300
Brands so who knows you might win
something and now let's show her the
game this is the puzzle
pieces may we seate we celebrate uh we
divide into two part and uh have our
audience to uh get more answer all right
so this is the buzzle game
and all right yeah and the reward for
this game is the vouchers that can be
replaced for cash applicable for over
300 friends and behind the puzzle please
like a team picture subjecting the main
keyword mhm you found it familiar with
you is it familiar with you yeah and the
first and the most correct respondent to
find out the main keyword will receive
the highest value voucher and the six
puzzle piece here correspond to six
keywords and also serving as the general
hint for the main keywords all right so
to unveil these buzle pieces and this
clo part parts of the team picture we
need to complete some small challenges
every challenge come with a voucher gift
for the attendees who successfully solve
it so very simple right so we have six
keywords over here all right so uh our
task is to
uh unveil each puzzle pieces and then we
have the final keyword all right so are
you ready do you understand the rules of
the game very simple right okay all
right so now I will give you the first H
for the main keyword okay the clue for
the main keyword is as follow it is an
English noun consisting of 14 letter all
right English a noun English now 14
letters this is the main keyword all
right all right I repeat the main
keyword is 14 letter English now all
right and the keywords on the puzzle
pieces are all related to this main
keyword please remember this hint 14
letter English now all right all right
so now we move to the first pu pieces it
see
digitalization all right so what is the
challenge for
digitalization puzzle okay the challenge
is convert the number
from decimal to
Binary who can very simple
[Music]
19 yes Whoever has the correct answer
please raise your hand quickly to reveal
the puzzle piece and earn yourself a
voucher all right I can see the first
hand here all right right 19 from
decimal to
boundary yeah
five the Google told me that it's going
to be
101 101
oh repeat
please 101 101 101
101 is it
EXA is there 101
101 right 101 101
nearly correct but not
correct else else who
can convert
19 I repeat 19 not 90 right 19 all right
1 0 01
1 exactly
congratulations okay
19 convert from decimal to Binary is
1 1 one and you get a voucher
congratulations for the first winner
very simple right and let's try again
let's try again yes and the number 19
correspond to 19 life insurance
companies currently operating in Vietnam
yeah y 19 we have 19 life insurance
all right so now we will move to the
next veral technology and the challenge
is we will have a video clip and in this
video clip we have
total my microphone hello hello all
right so in this video clip we have
totally a keyword so your ti is to try
to remember the whole a k word and tell
us all right very simple right so now
please draw your attention to the screen
and now we will project the video clip
1 2
please first
[Music]
one
finish a work all right I see the
[Music]
hand all the microphon is out all right
it's come back it's back need to change
no all right just give him the
[Music]
microphone all right so we have AK world
oh you take notes very fast okay and now
please shout out the E the 8K word our
Predictive Analytics AI machine learning
inch big data powerbi profet and CH GPT
congratulations perfectly thank you and
you have a voucher
congratulations
all right so this is the second buzzos
is unveiled
now but during the time who can guess
the man CER right yeah just raise your
hand and tell
us so you can tell the main keyword
right so I think I think um the main
keyword is
infrastructure
infrastructure 14 letter infrastructure
is your final answer
right here I is it
exactly let me check
infrastructure um so sorry it's not
infrastructure okay we can try later all
right so now we've moved to the third
puzzle to find out the keyword of the
Third piece please rearrange the
following letters into a complete word
let's see okay let's see the following
letters and please rearrange it yeah
okay we give him another chain
yeah okay my lady first
right hi the answer is machine
learning is there any correct
answer else because exactly machine
learning thank you so much and
congratulations yes all right
congratulations the answer is machine
learning very simple right so any all
right so I will have a ladies that can
guess the final main keywords of the puz
game
right you
sure
uh
transformation
transformation how many letter 14 sure
let me
check so the main keyword is
[Music]
transformation
transformation right Mission
oration
Miss let count it we just have four
letter we missions or
Mas Mas s or no s no s no s
transformation
exactly
congratulations so the main final
keyword of this puzz game is
transform so you will have the biggest
voucher of the game thank you so much
but we still we still have to open to
unveil the rest of the puzzle right
congr to you did great all right so now
we move to the generative AI yes and
this is a photo of celebrity generated
by Ai and anyone who correctly gets the
names of these three stars can win a
voucher easy
right all right I can see our beautiful
lady
here who is on the
screen um the first is B
the second is Maria Korea and the third
is an Jolie you saw what the girl in the
middle Mariah kry
right exactly
congratulations you will receive a
vouchers from the organizer thank you so
much and a voucher for you and now we
move to
analytic please check this spreadsheet
and let us know the read that of the
following
calculation is it familiar with
Actuarial just take your time all
right
[Music]
anything
anyone what finished your calculation
please raise your
hand and earn you with a voucher for
from the
[Music]
organizer this is
a okay he's back
again I think 16 16 16 not correct sorry
oh this is a negative
number I see negative so many so many
other all right a negative
number so not
thing let me double check okay just to
the quick calculation is it um negative
56 negative
exactly how can you count this um just
do a quick calculation on my phone
really H so you have an app on your
phone or like just a calculator on your
phone like calculator just a calculator
on your phone wow congratulations so
smart and you have a
voucher negative
56 ladies and
gentlemen yes and Fast and Furious is
exactly describe the actuario expert
right and now to the last challenge the
keyword of this puzzle piece is hidden
in the following picture this keyword
consists of more than 10 letters who
overi what it is please quickly raise
your hand to answers 10
letters the 10
letters more than sorry more than 10
later it's
modernization where is it where is
it it's in a brow from the bottom from
the bottom right and in the middle right
modernization do we have any any word
else anywh else that more than 10
later okay anyone can you see the
modernization exactly congratulations
all right modernization congratulations
yes and please give her the
vouchers thank you so much all right so
we finished the buzz game and our final
keyword is
transformation ladies and gentlemen
thank you so much for your great
cooperating and you are all so smart so
clever right yes and hope I hope the
game help uplift the atmosphere Here and
Now please come back to the actual AAL
topics with the advancement of modern
technology and E benchmarking
transformation has become imperative for
the insurance industry the great
transformation will facilitate
development and Innovation undoubtedly
leading the explosive grow and thank you
everyone for actively participating in
today's afternoon
game and now Kylie return ladies and
gentlemen data analytics is an integral
process in the actuary scope of work
this is also our next topic modern
analytics in insurance we want welcome
the next presentation made by Dr David
Jimmer Candon lead analytics and Senior
data scientist jenry please
welcome hey um first first of all thank
you very much for this wonderful
transition I was really afraid that I
would have to stand up here and talk
about data analytics until someone uh
tells you their life story and how they
kind of beat All Odds so um I'm very
thankful that we kind of had this
transition now um today I want to talk a
little bit about uh modern data
analytics um so I think it's a term that
everyone kind of has a general
understanding um but I want to first
introduce a couple of key Concepts and
then afterwards I want to give a couple
of examples that we have conducted in
the
past so um I want to keep it at a very
high level at the same time I want to
have a very concrete example and so I
want to start by just assuming that we
have different ages and for each
different ages we have some kind of data
point that we are interested in I just
said here claims data uh claims cost but
it could be anything really that is uh
of interest to us what we want to do is
we want to predict something right this
is just raw data and if we look at this
raw data um we just have raw data we
cannot use it until we do something with
it some transformation or some
simplification of it that allows us to
apply it to new data and I think most of
you are familiar with what we could do
um if we have a new data point so for
example a new applicant or so and we
know their age then we want to predict
what the associated cost is um so there
are many different ways how we can do it
um the easiest one and one of the most
well understood I would say is just thr
throw a line through the data right uh I
think especially the younger Generations
in the room will all heard of or will
all heard of uh linear regression um the
older generation probably in the job and
not at Uni but um this is something that
we do all day every day right so there's
nothing new yet right I'm just trying to
set the stage for the later models that
we are talking
about so what we do is we have some
algorithm um that gives the parameters
for this line and um then we can read
the data or plug the new data in and get
a prediction from that so for this
specific point we have a given value I
mean no magic here it's just you know
very very basic but very
interesting um the big question that we
always have and that we'll never get rid
of is does it actually fit our data and
this is a problem or a question that
will always pop up it doesn't matter
what kind of model you use it doesn't
matter what kind of uh models you use
around it or methodologies you use
around it you will always have to ask
yourself the question is this actually
right and I think in this case we can
all agree that this is probably not the
right fit right so we can see that we
have um that the values are going up um
but the linear nature of this line
doesn't really capture the data um so
what can we do um one thing that we
quite often like to do is we transform
the data um in this case we apply a
nonlinear transformation and all of a
sudden we have another line it's still
called linear regression in this case um
but that is only because we transformed
the data and so we still draw a line
through the transformed
space um and in this case we
can have make the same predictions and
we see it seems to be a little bit
better the
so does it fit better maybe maybe not it
depends really on our uh what we want to
do with the data in the end right if we
just want to have a nice plot and we
want to interpret the values then this
might be good if we want to have like
the the best performing model because we
this is related to our pricing or so
then we probably want to make it a
little bit more
accurate so one thing that we do is we
can imitate what humans often do and
this is we create a decision tree that
is we make up rules and based on the
rules we set the values so in this case
we can make a very simple one where we
just say okay if the age is below a
certain value we pick one value if the
age is above another value we pick
another
value so this is a huge benefit of that
is it's very easy to explain right the
Eli 5 so explain it to me like M5 is
really easy because like oh you're there
pick that value you're there pick that
value so it's really nice
um is one break point good enough
probably not so what we can do is we can
extend that so in this case we just ask
two questions or we have one H but we
have three different steps there and
then we just segmented in multiple ways
now of course these are what we would
call hyperparameters which is a
wonderful term that basically hides
everything that it does what we mean by
that it's it's something that we can
arbitrarily set I now have uh three
different distinctions three different
questions I could make a thousand I
could make two so we can play around
with that later if we wanted to but the
general idea we have now something that
we would call a decision
tree um and typically a decision tree is
not this list of rules that we have just
seen But we would visualize the data if
we wanted to in a proper decision tree
so this is for
example the decision tree that we would
then
see so we could follow along so if the
AG is smaller than 40 and the AG is
larger than 20 then we would predict 50k
I mean all the values are made up right
but you kind of hopefully get the
general concept of what we're trying to
achieve
here one of the or there multiple
extensions that we can use here so we
can have multiple trees we can have
different depth of trees so most of you
might have heard about something called
XG boost so kind of booster trees or
back trees like random forest and so on
these are basically just iterations of
this concept
right um but as I mentioned earlier we
try to make it a little bit easier for
us humans to understand um and follow
therefore our human approach to these
kind of problems um and what is closer
to our human understanding than actually
the brain itself right so we try to
mimic how our Baran works and um I'm not
uh um I'm not in medicine but I think we
all know we have neurons in our brain
they're connected they fired together
and by firing together we can make
decisions it's probably a very gross
under uh understatement of the
complexity of our brain um we have tried
to replicate that and I think by all by
by now this is no news that we have
artificial neural networks because
everyone has heard about it right we
just saw lots of these terms on the uh
on the board here um the interesting
part is about neural networks that they
they are very good at specific tasks um
so what we see here is we have these
connections and we see all of these
small lines here are parameters in this
case maybe they're 40 parameters or
something like this um recently we've
had huge advancements in this field um I
mean by now um a year ago I would have
asked who of you has used jet GPT before
I think by now the question is boring
because I think everyone will say yes to
that right so just an very interesting
data point for us to keep in mind that
how quick this field has
expanded um so this chart was uh 3 years
old by now um and there we saw that the
biggest model here proposed by Microsoft
had a whopping 17.5 billion parameters
if you save that to your hard drive it
will be a big file basically right so
it's like it's a very large data set and
by now if we scale that down the latest
version of jgpt GP jgpt 4 has 1.7
trillion so it's a lot bigger I mean we
have all seen these stories so I think
they are not really uh that surprising
um for us I think it's interesting these
deep neural networks how complex they
are they are very good at certain tasks
but they're not so good at other tasks
um because one thing that we always have
to keep in mind um especially in our
industry there are certain parts where
we need to be able to explain what we
are doing and how a certain decision was
made If I decline a person in
underwriting I need to be able to
explain to them why I declined them I
cannot say oh I have this algorithm here
and this algorithm said no I have to say
Okay well you know you clicked in the
underwriting this and this question as
yes and so therefore we decline you
right so this model understanding or
explainability as we call it in the
industry um is something that we need to
be aware
of
um so I have very briefly kind of uh
rounded up three different types of
models so we have linear models we have
decision trees and we have uh neural
networks um I think everyone is kind of
especially in the last couple of years
wanted to go into uh deep networks or
neural networks or artificial
intelligence as it's sometimes called um
because this is where all the cool kids
wanted to go which is like you know the
the area that also had the biggest um
advancements um most of our or at least
my day job is at least uh working with
tabular data and so we have played
around with uh neural networks but most
of the time we found that they're
actually not that good at tabular data
so tabul data basically is data that you
can put in Excel more or less right you
have kind of rows you have columns and
you want to run some algorithm on it so
one thing that I've kept from you so far
is um when we tried earlier with the
claims cost that is something that we
call a regression problem because we try
to predict a continuous value we can
also have a classification where we
predict uh discrete classes so for
example whether a person should uh be
declined or not and um what we can then
do is we create this Matrix here and
kind of look at in which parts are which
algorithms actually any good and what we
see is that linear models in decision
trees typically not always but typically
excel in regression and classification
tasks um that is most of the time also
due to the data size because rarely do
we see a data set where we have like oh
we have a data set of 100 million lives
like that's not really how our industry
works unfortunately in some
cases um and these noral networks if we
have a Neal network with a couple of
billion parameters that means we have to
have general rur of Thum a couple of
million data points as well which is
very hard in our industry
typically um there are however just uh
so that you don't or that you don't
wonder why I uh don't like Neal Network
works I do it's just that they're very
good in different ones so if you have
for example image recognition or natural
language processing or what we call a I
know so um jgpt for example if I were to
put a linear model versus uh jgpt yeah I
think we all know how that would go
right so
um one dimension of every data project
is always the algorithm right the
algorithm that I've just shown you are a
very good start and there are loads of
things that you can change and extend on
but the realities of our business is
always we work in a corporation which is
good typically but uh corporations means
that we have to take lots of other
things into considerations as well so
what do we actually need for a
successful analytics project well first
of all I always try to start out with an
actionable goal that means in the end I
want to understand what kind of goal I
could achieve with this and can we
actually act on this if the goal all of
a sudden is well we need to be the
biggest company in the market like yeah
sure we're trying that already I cannot
really act on that right so therefore we
want to make sure that we have a goal
that we can actually not only achieve
but that we can also work
towards we need to have the Buy in of
stakeholders that not only means that we
have um our management or higher man
higher management depending on the
project size um but Al so often times
our data is stored away so we need to
have the stakeholders that know where
the data is how to merge the data what
the data stands for where the data
problems are and so on they typically
need to be involved as well because we
have a saying in in the industry garbage
in garbage out you can have the best
algorithm in the world but it won't be
able to help you anything if your data
is not good
right um which kind of uh brings this
point home suitable data um I always
joke that if you give me data dat about
STS then I cannot predict you how many
people are born right so there is no
relationship between the two so
therefore even if I very good data the
data is not suitable so therefore the
whole Pro uh project is
void and last but not least uh
methodolog methodological expertise so
if you want to venture into the deeper
ends of this one so for example if you
want to train or fine train some of
these models you need to have experts in
this specific field that are then
capable of interpreting the results
because quite often you have a very
powerful weapon um but it's also a very
easy weapon to shoot yourself in the
foot with and so therefore you need to
be careful about what you do but um
there are wonderful resources out there
and it's a very nice community that we
have in data science in general um where
there's lots of collaboration and uh
lots of exchange of ideas and methods as
well um coming or bringing all of this
into the insurance industry um I
typically like to follow the typical
customer Journey so in the beginning the
customer becomes aware of the product um
and kind of maybe seeks more information
then at one point they apply um so they
undergo the underwriting and internally
we apply the pricing um then we have the
policy servicing so the customer is then
the
client um the policy is basically in
force um maybe we want to reach out for
them for some cross- selling um or worst
case they might want to cancel the
policy and last not but not least we
might have uh claims as well um so the
question is which of these parts are
actually or can be used in combination
with data science or AI to uh to enhance
this whole
journey and just some examples the
awareness is a big thing right so I
think when I ask lots of insurance
companies some of them say no we don't
really use Advanced Data analytics and
my first answer is typically well you
probably have some kind of marketing
right and most of the companies
especially in the internet age use
Google or in Google analytics and this
is basically already very complicated um
uh data science that happens most of the
time behind the
scenes um underwriting and pricing I
think no one is surprised if I say that
this is also field that you where you
can use uh data analytics quite heavily
um in policy servicing we have other
products so kind of cross- selling that
we can do there um we have uh we could
could do a project to predict the
cancellation of policies um and then in
claims we can have waste fored abuse
detection or similar methods that
actually look at claims in more
details so here I've just listed out the
a couple of different possible uh
projects and last but not least before I
uh leave the stage of I wanted to walk
you through two projects that we have
done that are uh in this area so the
first one is around underwriting
triaging and the second one is about
crossselling
now um the first project the
underwriting triaging project was in
individual life of high Networth
individuals um and the problem was that
we had a very complicated underwriting
process so I think 700 plus pages per
each application
and I guess you all know what kind of
resources went into this when you have
700 pages that you need to read through
to figure out what the relevant
information
is um so our goal was that we wanted to
lower our underwriting expenses and we
also wanted or by lowering the time
spent on each
case um we translated that into the
analytics goal which is we wanted to
have a rule that was able to Auto
decline or Tri the different uh cases in
such a way that the human underwriter
could then focus on the most relevant
cases if you know that this person is
going to be declined then you can give
it to the human and the human knows okay
I just need to through it quickly read
through it fine we can Auto decline it
um and similarly if we have very easy
cases the rule system can also or the
human can also say um okay the system
says this is a very likely case that
this is actually a good case so
accept
um in this case we actually had a very
nice data set so we had very rich
historical data of underwriting
decisions that we could then use and
um we used um for the Curious of you we
used a combination of a classification
problem and also supervised machine
learning um that means we had both
linear trees and this tree based models
sorry linear models and tree based
models and so basically the two models
that I've introduced to you
earlier and in the end what we were a
able to do is come up with a simplified
decision tree so we tried out different
rules or different models and one of the
interesting Parts is that we wanted to
understand the rules very well and so
therefore we limited ourselves to a very
simple algorithm because the simple
algorithm we could then go to our
experts in underwriting and say okay
this is what the machine thinks is this
something that you agree with if we had
gone for a very complicated um deep
neuron Network then we wouldn't be able
to create such a simple graph it might
have been a little bit more performant
but this performance comes at the cost
that we don't understand the model and
so in this case we decided to go for a
very simple decision tree um but that
then helped us to basically accelerate
this whole
process the second project that I wanted
to talk to you about is a crossselling
from Health to life so we had an
existing um Health portfolio and we
wanted to figure out which of these
people are most likely to buy into a
life portfolio or to buy a life policy
um so uh again we had a very nice data
set so um especially in health you
typically have lots of information about
each P patient um so that is a in this
case it was a big plus for us um because
we could train the model on very rich
medical history
um we had in this case something that is
called unsupervised learning which is
something that typically gives you a
headache because unsupervised learning
means you have you don't really know
what your target is you don't have this
one column oh this person actually
bought something but you have to look or
train the algorithm on the data
and for the lack of a better term hope
that it does the right thing you do lots
of coordination you do lots of
controlling of the whole problem so that
the model actually does what you think
it does or what you want it to do um but
therefore I say it gives you lots of
headache because you need to make sure
that it actually does what you think
it's doing
um so what we found is that um
unsurprisingly people who didn't have
any health claims are have a lot lower a
over e values um so these are very good
candidates for um uh simplified
underwriting or basically just make them
an offer for a uh life
policy but there is already I mean
that's kind of an I wouldn't say
no-brainer but it's a very easy thing
that or a solution I think that uh
people would have come up with um
without looking at the data in that
detail but the interesting part is that
we then looked at the people that
already had claims and we were able to
segment them and in this case we
segmented them not only by the actual
AOE value that we expect that we saw
later on but also that the average years
until death and in this case we saw that
there are a couple of
clusters and um we kind of made out the
groups that had very severe claims and
very mild claims so for example if you
have accident caused by a machine that's
not really going to be a long-term issue
um however if you have like malignant
brain tumor that's a whole other story
right so again it's not really that uh
we were blown away by the results but
the results helped us to automate
something that was very hard to do on a
manual
process um so what of the main takeaways
from my talk today um data data driven
decision- making is at the core of our
industry's future I really believe in
that um it will help us to automate the
not so interesting Parts I would say of
the business um so that we can spend our
resources on the ones that are actually
really important to
us um data analytics is a competitive
Advantage um so if we are good at data
analytics that means that we can excel
in other areas a lot better uh and last
not but least data projects require a
multidisciplinary um Team or experts in
this case um so if you only have people
from one area in there then you
typically become too focused on one
thing but if you have multiple experts
in there or multidisiplinary team then
it's a lot more fruitful because you can
kind of figure out what the the other
team or with the other person what their
Viewpoint is and you can incorporate
that into your
process
and that's it from my side
[Music]
[Applause]
today all right thank you so much we
very appreciate all the useful
information from our gener
representative Dr David jiman Kanda and
now we are very pleased to invite
everyone to ask question our guest on
this topic any question from you
please uh raise your hand and we will
provide a
microphone any question ladies and
gentlemen with a very interesting topic
modern analytics in
insur yes and if you have any questions
related to this topic
yeah okay please uh give the microphone
to uh Our Ladies from at the back
[Music]
uh thank you doctor thank you sh for a
very interesting
sharings uh you see for data analytics
you I have two questions yeah please the
first one you know we have so many
algorithm to analyze data so here you
just prevent trees for the
linear model tra Trace B model and uh
deep learnings with neuron Network how
about the other for other metals like uh
glass for classification you also have
um K&N or so many other algorithms
sometimes quite simple but very
effective to deal with data how why not
you don't use the other algorithms and
the second question in so I work for a
university I'm a lecturer I teach data
science to my student and we we really
need the real life data like this for my
student to practice with the real case
so do we have any opportunity to asset
to the Kay projects for my students they
can do research or they can do practice
with the real data so if if we can asset
that kind of project like this thank you
very much um so so to the first question
um why didn't we use other models so for
example you brought up Kens that are
also svms and by now it feels like it's
just a soup of abbreviations which it
kind of is um and it was a mix of
business reality um we didn't have too
much time so at one point we just needed
to say okay stop we have we think that
we have results that are good enough um
so we often times made the experience
that if we use a linear model which we
typically do as a first step um that it
is already very well performing it's not
the best right you can still squeeze a
couple of percentage points out of uh
more complicated models but you you win
the accuracy but you lose the
explainability and often times we then
say okay actually although we have this
very complicated model here that has a
couple of percentage points more we
actually stick with a simple linear
model because we're able to explain it
and um our experts can look at it and
say okay this is actually valid um
because this is kind of the if you think
about it too deeply then you can kind of
get into this whole turnover that you
think okay is my model actually
predicting what I think it is um this is
worse with unsupervised learnings but
even with supervised learnings you have
the problem that you don't really know
what the model is doing especially in
complicated models um so therefore in
this case we stuck with the simpler
models I would say although the tree
based models can be very complicated as
well um regarding the projects um I
think let's chat up afterwards maybe we
find
something
yeah we have some sorry yeah I how about
the second question so I am a lecturer
from University of Economics H City and
so we have some subject rate to data
ltis for example data science or
SRM uh so we need data and sometime our
student need opportunity to practice
with the real data so can you create
some opportunity for our student to
practice to do research with these kind
of data than you yeah so we have run
into the problem of not missing data but
missing data sets especially public ones
right because especially when I give
workshops or so I oftentimes want to
show real data but of course I cannot
show real data um so there are a couple
of data sets out there but most of them
that I know of are non-life
which doesn't or defeats the purp a
little bit um we played around with
simulating the data um I mean you
wouldn't get any real value out of it
but that's not really the point right
you want to play around with it
especially in this academic context um
we didn't finish the project because
it's not really a high priority priority
um maybe we'll pick it up again um but
uh maybe we can take this off stage and
then talk about it later today if you're
okay with that yes yeah thank you very
much thank
you thank you so much for your questions
all right so any
question any question else related to
Modern analytic in
Insurance okay thank you so should you
have any concerns you can send to the
organizer and we will send to our expert
afterwards okay we we still have more
question all right so okay so we will
have a another
question
hello hello my name is nam and I'm from
uh potential data analytics team um
actually um in our teams there's a lot
of people coming from other industry
they're coming from e-commerce and they
also coming from lmcg and uh when they
join potential Joy insurance industry
they realize that one of the biggest
different is the lacking of the data
because uh for EVC J eCommerce right um
we will predict in the short very short
term like one week two week to see the
customer behavior however in insurance
for example when we predict the life
expectancy or mortality we use the
historic data of people who have been
born who have born like 30 or 40 years
ago with very different lifestyle uh in
uh condition of living and then we apply
it for the people who already like 20
just 20 years old now and we predict it
for the next 20 or 30 years so my
question is how do you think about the
lagging and then the accuracy in the
modeling in Insurance compared to other
industry yeah yeah you raised a very
valid point that uh we have very little
data especially if you divide the number
of row that you have by the number of
people typically it's one right um if
you think about something like an online
shop they have like a gazillion amount
of data points for each interaction so
they probably know what website you
visited before and they can buy data dat
to kind of uh put that into it as well
um this is one of the many reasons that
I like the simpler models as well
because if I have 100,000 data points I
cannot train a model with 200,000
parameters right so um if I have then
very simplistic linear uh linear
regression with maybe five or 10
different parameters um which is almost
already considered a complicated linear
regression right but it's just 10
parameters so it's a lot easier to
understand and to kind of
guess the the the correctness of the
model as well um so that is one thing
how we typically deal with it um
sometimes or you must have come across
um the another very big problem is that
most of the data that we have is very
skewed it's very unbalanced um I always
joke that it's very bad for the
algorithm it's very good for the people
and for our business as well that most
people don't die or most people in our
data sets didn't die yet just good for
the people um um but typically an
algorithm performs best If the ratio
between positive and negative cases is
0.5 I mean if you had a data set that
where 50% of the people already died I
think um that would be very hard on your
business um
so it's a very hard problem and I'm
afraid I cannot give you one answer that
will satisfy that um we try to work
around it as I said by simp using simple
models um sometimes we able to enhance
the data maybe there are other data
sources um there is something like
synthetic data that one can look into
but in the end you're just making up
data based on existing data and so
sometimes it works a little bit but most
of the time you create noise in your
data
set okay thank you so much meter David J
merman CER from jenry and we hope that
the answer and the spech of meet of Dr
David will give you was give you an
interesting uh picture about modern
analytic and insurance and please remain
on the state to receive our appreciation
flower and we would like to invite M
mashi Edo representative of organizer to
come onto the stage and present flower
to guest
[Music]
speaker once again thank you so much Dr
David Gman colander jary representative
for your great
and attending today with us thank you
please give a big round of
applause thank you thank you Dr David
and thank you Mr
masi and Now ladies and gentlemen before
we move on to the next part we are going
to have a 15minute break and we invite
you to enjoy once again a te break and a
design uh area outside and the event
will resume at
3:30 p.m. so please return to into the
state area secure your seat by
32 p.m. to inser the program on time
schedule thank you so much and I'll
please enjoy thank you enjoy your meal
and have a good rest thank you and see
you
[Music]
again
welcome everyone back to our program
following the teams of Vietnam act Aro
conference 2023 events
is the next topic revolving around
elevating Insurance risk assessment
particularly with the application of
machine learning in underwriting and
insurance risk
prediction and please welcome on the
stage Mr Jal manager of data science
from Pacific library Asia to share the
Insight on the
topic pleas me give a big round Applause
to welcome Mr
[Music]
chihan
testing hello good afternoon everyone
thank you for joining our discussion
today on using machine learning model to
predict Insurance risk it sounds a bit
complicated but trust me is easier to
understand than the latest memes on the
internet today we stand on on the edge
of a new era of exur science where
emerging Technologies and new data
sources are beginning to redefine our
way of risk
prediction as actes we understand the
importance of accurate risk prediction
especially for maintaining the financial
stabilities of the insurance company and
ensuring fair pricing for our policy
holders we have traditionally rely on
some statistical techniques to analyze
risk and they have serve us pretty well
but hey the world is changing fast and
all the new technologies and data
sources are calling us to try something
new therefore in today discussion we'll
explore the world of machine learning
and we'll see how this powerful
technique can help to make our insurance
industry
better before we dive in let's take a
quick look on our agenda
today we'll first begin with a brief
introduction about machine
learning then we'll look into two real
world examples of how machine learning
can be applied in the insurent industry
our first use case is about predi
underwriting which will explore how
machine learning can help to streamline
our underwriting
process following that in the Second Use
case we'll explore an application of
machine learning for modality analysis
and prediction which is something more
relevant to the work we do as
exies in the last part we'll wrap up our
discussion by discussing the implication
and opportunities that this advancement
have brought to our beloved insurent
industry sorry the button doesn't
work
okay yeah so without further Ado um
let's start our discussion today in the
first section we'll give a brief
introduction about machine
learning so what is machine learning
here is one definition that I personally
like about machine learning is actually
a subset of the big family of AI and it
is all about using algorithms to learn
patterns from the data and then use
those patterns to make
prediction to simplify it you can think
of it as how we human learn from our
experience for example when we see dark
clouds in the sky we know that in my
Ranson based on our past
observation machine learning does
something similar but instead of using
intuition
it used mathematical algorithms to learn
from data which we see how this work in
more details
later also you might be wondering why
machine learning is so powerful and why
should we start considering to apply it
in our insurance industry here are some
of the
reasons to begin with just like many
other industry our insurance industry
has also experience a data explosion in
this digital era for example the advanc
in health system and underwriting R
engine have provided us with electronic
health record and underwriting data like
never
before these data sets are usually High
dimensional and very complex and our
traditional methods often struggle to
handle them
effectively machine learning on the
other hand is very effective at
analyzing this data set and making it a
very powerful tool for comprehensive
analysis furthermore together with high
dimensional data machine learning allows
for a more personalized approach in risk
assessment as we'll see later this open
the door for a more customized solution
that better fits with the customer needs
and risk
profile last but not least machine
learning can also help to support our
decision making by providing us with
insights and recommendation based on
what it has learn from the
data this can help to improve the
efficiency of some operational process
um in the insurance industry including
sales and marketing underwriting and
claim management and
Etc talking about this um let's look
into some of the real world examples our
first use case is about predi
underwriting as we all know underwriting
is the first and critical layer of
Defense in our life insurance
industry however sometimes dedicating
extensive resource to manual
underwriting can be challenging
especially when there's a huge number of
of insurance
application today we would like to share
about a real project that I had the
privilege to work on in the past for
background our client is actually one of
the largest life insurance company in
their countries and they have already
implemented a very robust underwriting
rule engine which helped to straight
through process more than half of their
insurance
application however there still a
significant portion of their application
require manual underwriting
based on the underwriting rules set by
the
company also as you can see from the
graph here the number of insurance
application is still rapidly increasing
each year because of business
growth this has created multiple
challenges especially to the
underwriters you can imagine that if the
underwriting team does not grow at the
same scale it may cause overwhelming War
lots to the underwriters together with
many other negative
effects also so these issues met us to
think about a question on resource
allocation like should the underwriters
spend the same level of efforts to all
cases or is there a way to help
allocating more resources to the
underwriting of more complex
cases all these challenges together have
emphasized the need for us to reconsider
our approach in traditional
underwriting the good news is that with
the advanc in technology machine
learning turned out to be a potential
solution to help addressing these
challenges and that's what we explore in
this section
today before we go into the details um
Let me give a high level overview of
underwriting process in our life
insurance
industry typically when an insurance
application is submitted it will go
through an initial assessment by the
underwriting rule
engine at this stage some of the
applicants may get a direct decision
like a standard offer or a
declination however there will also be a
group of applicants with specific
complication that the rot engine May
refer them to the underwriters for
manual
underwriting the underwriter will then
decide if the applicant is a standard or
substandard
life at the bottom we show how a machine
learning model can be embedded into the
process basically we can deploy a
machine learning model to predict the
underwriting decision of these
applicants before they are revealed by
the
underwriters the main idea here is that
for those applicants who receive a very
good score from the model they can then
be directly be offered with standard
issuance without further need of manual
underwriting on the other hand for those
applicants who do not receive a very
good score from the model they will
still need to go through the manual
underwriting by the underwriter to reach
an underwriting
decision this part is the same as the
original process however the number of
cases for manual underwriting has
already been reduced thanks to the
machine learning
model now let's look into the details of
the model that perform the task as
discussed earlier the primary objective
of the model is to predict the
underwriting outcome of these applicants
before they are revealed by the
underwriters depending on the use cases
the targeted applicants are usually
those applicants that require manual
underwriting for these applicants the
target of the model is to predict their
underwriting decision that will be made
made by the underwriter which will
generally fall into either standard or
substandard
category again depending on the use
cases the definition of substandard can
be when the applicant get any of the
loading exclusion or declination from
the
underwriter conversely standard is when
none of these condition
apply furthermore we usually need to
train different model for the
underwriting of different benefits like
live CI TBD or Med IND due to the
different nature in their
underwriting also the model will require
specific information for it to make
prediction basically it will rely on all
the available information provided in
the submitted application including
demographics policy information and
declarations for some use cases that
involve existing customer it is also
common for us to include their history
records like their claim and
underwriting record in the past for the
model to learn just like how a human
underwriter will access an
individual finally with all this
information the model can then predict
the likelihood of each applicant to
receive a standard outcome ranging from
0o to
100% this likelihood can then be
translated into underwriting decision by
setting a trold such that those
applicants with likelihood higher than
this threshold can then May directly be
offered with standard issuance without
further need of manual
underwriting setting the value of this
threshold is fully flexible and it
depends on the risk appetite of the
company which we won't go into further
details
today in overall this concept of predi
underwriting has started to gain
popularity in the insurent industry and
here are some of the
reasons firstly predictive underwriting
can help to improve the straight through
true processing or STP rate by reducing
the number of cases for manual
underwriting which can help to reduce
the workloads of the
underwriter furthermore a higher STP
rate can contribute to higher sales and
policy takeup rate this is because a
lower waiting time can help to improve
customer satisfaction and reduce their
chances of dropping out during the
application
process last but not least
it is also worth mentioning that those
applications that are straight through
process by the machine learning model
are typically the straightforward
cases this means that the machine
learning model can actually help the
underwriters in triaging their cases and
allowing them to allocate more of their
time to the underwriting of more complex
cases therefore resulting in better
resource
allocation now we'll move on to our
Second Use case which is to use machine
learning for modality analysis and
prediction as actuaries we have been
mainly focusing on only a few factors
like Edge gender for the pricing and
valuation purposes of our insurance
product however in this digital era we
have the chance of getting more
information about the individuals and it
is worth for us to start exploring if we
can incorporate all this new information
to achieve a more granular and
comprehensive risk assessment
to illustrate this we would like to
share about a modality analysis that we
have done by using machine learning
model on a very powerful data
set the data set is actually a
population data that contains variety of
information about the individuals which
we can see them in a few
category the first category is
demographics uh which cover basic
personal details like age gender smoking
status and
Etc then we also have the health
assessment information of the individual
this include basic clinical measurements
like BMI and blood pressure as well as
laboratory results um such as those
biomarkers that are collected from the
blood and urine sample of the individual
like blood cholesterol blood sugar and
Etc this type of information is now more
accessible to us than in the past
because of electronic health
record also the factors so far are
pretty standard for health related
analysis but now we have our third
category variable
Technologies in this data set some of
the individuals were also asked to wear
a physical activity monitor you can
think of it as a device like Fitbit or
Apple watch which mainly recorded down
their number of steps taken and sleep
duration per
day this type of information is
relatively new to our industry but
started to be used in some Wellness
product in some
markets lastly and most importantly um
the data set also has the modality
information of the
individuals this information allow us to
do a modality analysis and to do that we
have trained a machine learning model on
this data set which can help us to
better understand how all these
variables like demographics Health
assessment and varable Technologies
linked to the person
morality now let's look into some of the
interesting findings from our modality
model there has been a hot topic of
discussion about how much activity
engagement matter for our health
especially when compared to the
traditional
factors in this modality model one of
the factors we included is called
average number of steps taken per day
which is clearly a measure for physical
activity
level and guess what we found from the
variable importance other than hge
Factor this number number of Step Factor
turn out to be the most important factor
in explaining our mortality
experience you can see that it beats all
the traditional factors that we have
included in our model including BMI
blood pressure and even smoking status
which all of these have been commonly
used in our life insurance
industry the graph on the right also
shows with some useful information we
can see that there will be a steep
increase in mortality rate when the
number of steps is lower than around
7,500 per
day these results have shown us that
physical activity engagement is indeed
very important in promoting our Health
and
Longevity also with this data set uh we
can do some analysis on traditional
factors as well here we show a sample
interaction between H and
BMI these two graph are basically the
same just that one of them is a 3D plot
and the other is a quter plot the X AIS
here represent the h factor y AIS
represent the BMI factor and the gs's or
the color intensity represent the
multiplier in mortality
R from this graph we can observe how the
effect of BMI changes across the
ages at younger ages the high BMI is the
primary concern that's what we all know
however as we grow older we can see that
the high BMI become less of
concern while low BMI start to have
higher effect on mortality rate we won't
go into further details on the medical
concept behind this but this modeling
results can actually help us to refine
our underwriting guidelines like
determining the appropriate loadings for
policy holders that are overweight in
different Edge
group so these are some of the high
level findings from our morality model
now we will shift our Focus back to the
real world application
by demonstrating a sample tool that we
have developed the sample tool is simply
called modality risk calculator you can
think of it as a fancy Health checkup
but instead of going to doctor we have
an AI model to do the
evaluation and since this app require us
to switch to another program we have
actually pre-recorded for this part um
to e the logistic therefore I will be
sharing a video
now now let me you through the user
interface of this modality risk
calculator there are two main sections
input and
output the input sections can be further
split into multiple categories and we go
through them one by
one first we have product information it
is like choosing the suur and benefit
term of a modality Lum product and you
will see why we need this information
later next we have personal details
which cover the basic information like
age gender working status and Etc
similar to the basics that you would
found on the dating
profile following this we have lifestyle
this sections covers things like smoking
status alcohol behavior and physical
activity
status including the average number of
steps that we mentioned
earlier moving on we have B basic body
is examination which cover traditional
factors like BMI and blood pressure
values then we also have laboratory
result here we just show a few for
illustration purposes such as blood
cholesterol blood sugar and
Etc last but not least we have
pre-existing conditions they will cover
things like health and medical history
including hypertension high blood
cholesterol diabetes and many other
kinds of
declarations after filling in all this
input we can then hit the submit
button then within a second the machine
learning will generate the results which
we can view in the output
section in the output section first we
have the calculated
premium based on the given product
information earlier and the predicted
modality rate we can calculate the
personalized risk premium
of the input person and compare it to
the average of the
pool which are those individuals with
the same Edge and gender with with the
input person in our database we can
think of this risk to premium as How We
Do pricing
today next we have modality prediction
here we show the projected survival
curve the input person within the
benefit
ter also we can calculate the life
expectancy of the person and compare it
to the
average for example if you were 50 but
living like a 41 years old the model
will let you
know furthermore we have a peer
comparison here we show where the person
ranks among the peers which again are
those individuals having the same Edge
and gender with the input person so this
particular information is very useful
because we can use this percental
information to stratify the individual
into different RIS groups and make
different underwriting or even pricing
decisions on
them moving forward we have attribution
analysis here we use another model
explainability method to break down the
predicted morality rate by each of the
factors the bottom bars here shows the
average modality rate from the pi and
the top bar shows the predicted modality
rate of the inputed person
in the middle it shows how each of the
factors contribute to the difference
between the person and the
average here the green bars represent
the good factors that make the person to
have lower mortality rate than the PS
conversely the red bars are the bad
factors that cause a higher mortality
rate than the
Pierce for this specific example I have
purposely set the input person to be a
middle Edge male with is unmarried and a
bit lack of exercise and keeping all the
other factors being
okay as you can see the biggest red bar
here is coming from the number of steps
due to the lack of
exercise interesting also the second
biggest red bar is coming from the fact
that the individual is
unmarried indeed from our model we do
observe that the married individuals
tend to have lower morality rate than
the those remain
single it seems to be reasonable to me
because having a spouse mate make you to
have overall better diet and do less
unreasonable things that may increase
your morality
risk the strength of this attribution
analysis is that it can estimate and
quantify the impact brought by each of
the individual factors this become part
particular important when we move on to
our next section recommendation
based on the attribution analysis we can
select let's say the top three red
factors and use them to generate
recommendation for the
individual to illustrate um in this
example we can recommend the input
person to increase their number of steps
from the inputed value of 3,500 to
7,500 and get
married and do some moderate
activities
we can then calculate the Improvement in
mortality rate if all of these are
achieved and more importantly we can
also calculate the reduction in risk
premium because of the Improvement in
modality
rate remember that including marriage
here is actually just for a job we don't
actually recommend people to get into a
relationship just to lower their
mortality risk Although our data does
show that mer individuals tend to live
longer I hope this simple demonstration
has shown you the potential of such
machine learning tool for the insurance
companies this kind of tool may open the
door for more advanced risk assessment
and granular price policy
pricing for individuals it can help to
improve self awareness by providing
insights into their Health and Longevity
and potentially Inspire some lifestyle
changes to improve their
health
okay I hope you have enjoyed the video
and my AP apology I think the screen is
not quite clear and yeah um I hope the
slide will be shared to you later
because there will be all the snapshots
of all these uh slides u in the slide so
if you are interested yeah you can look
into the details in the slide later okay
I will carry
on so in the last part uh we will
explore the implications and
opportunities that this advancement have
brought to our insurance industry
the first is enhan risk
assessment as Illustrated in the use
cases earlier by using machine learning
we are looking at not just more accurate
prediction but also a more comprehensive
view of risk which can which can help us
to have a better segmentation of risk
profile the second is personalized
Insurance product this new advancement
have opened the door for a more
customized policy structure and premium
as exies we should consider whether it
is beneficial for us to move beyond our
traditional approach and adopt a more
precise and holistic view of Risk by
taking into account more risk factors of
individual furthermore there are also
new opportunity for engagement with our
customer with these Technologies we have
the chance to improve our customer
interaction by providing them with
additional values like um Health
coaching and incentivize for healthier
lifestyle this not only can create a
more engaged relationship with the
customer but could also manage the risk
of the insurance
company however with all this
advancement there comes the need for
expertise and
infrastructure the increase in data and
Technology will demand for many things
like um more robust it
infrastructure Advanced Data science
skills and stronger system to ensure
data security and
Etc so that marks the end for my sharing
today um I hope it give you some new
ideas on how we can potentially innovate
and evolve within our insurent industry
um thank you for your attention and feel
free to let me know if you have any
question thank
[Applause]
[Music]
you thank you very much for all the
sharing
from Pacific library Mr Sho so have any
question from
[Music]
everybody all right if not uh we would
like to invite Mr J please REM State and
we would like to invite Mr maso
representative of the organizer State
once again to to present the flower
booket to our guest speaker
today please give a big round Applause
give a big thank to Mr Cho from Pacific
library for your great information today
thank you so much thank you so much Mr
Mas all right now ladies and Gentlemen
let's refresh with an exciting lucky thr
game here's your chance to win a
valuable prizes based on the lucky
numbers you receive upon checkin so
please check your lucky number we have
three third prizes two second prizes and
one special prize up stay tuned to find
out the lucky sick attendees
today
everyone have you had your lucky draw in
your
hand so you have the Lucky Draw on right
all right yes and Please be aware that
it's drawing C out the number three
times three times only and if your lucky
draw is cold please bring it to the
state for verification it called if it
call more than three times with no
respond we will draw another number to
give the benefits to the next lucky
numbers
[Music]
okay all right now the Lu all growing
turn for the third prizes the gift is a
computer mouse we have three third
prizes and please welcome Mr WIA head of
capital and Actuarial Solutions of
Prudential Vietnam to go on the stage
and come up to the stage and find out
the three lucky number who got the T
pride in the first
scw so Mr H please all
right so three computer
mouse are you
ready all right M are you ready with
your
lucky turn around the the the the the
the lucky the first number is all
right the first dra is
140 let me keep for you
140 if your lucky number is called
please and please stand up go to the
stay with us all right congratulations
for the first lucky winners today with
the number 140 congratulations and the
next third
prizes belong
to yet ah we have two two draw so okay
and the next number is 1 1 4 1 14 who
has 11 14 in your hand 114 please oh the
same area all right okay
one4 yes and let's fight the last person
the last lucky person for the third
prize and the number is
180 18
180 okay all right congratulations
please turn it on
stage we have a check
140 and 180 Right
congratulations okay so now we have
three lucky winners with the third prize
and now Mr H will uh present the prizes
to our first three lucky winners let's
move to the center of St let move to the
[Music]
center
once again congratulations on your lucky
draw congratulations thank you so much
okay Mr P please remain Mr P please
remain to have it for the second priz as
well and next is the drawing turn for
the second prize the gift is a hmon
candle speak yeah hmon c speaker wow
very attractive and valuable prizes so
we have two second prizes so two
[Music]
throws yes the first
is75
congratulations all right on the first
person and
now
and now please find the next person for
the second
[Music]
prize the next is 3 5
352 right 352
352 the biggest the biggest number so
far right
3 5 2 first
time no 3 five two second
time and three five two t time and then
find next person cancel
okay H card speaker wow well the number
is 2 2 3 six 2 3
six two 3 six
no okay we call out 2 3 six the first
time 2 3 6 second
time and 2 3
6 T time all right once again we try to
find another throw it's difficult to
find the next person for the taken price
right okay the number is
98 right do you have
98 first
time no 98 second
time and
98 last time all
right we
[Music]
try Okay 2 1
7 2 1
7 no signal
217 do we have it all right
congratulations
finy
him and now M will represent the
organizer to
present wow so big prize Hammer Carden
speaker a very famous
brand congratulation please Jo me to
give Big R
BL thank you so much thank you so much
thank you so much Mr thank you and now
the final and the biggest rise will be
what is it the most special Pride today
the special pride
is an iPod Pro 11 in
256 gab wow who's going to be the
luckiest person of tonight and I would
like to invite Mr mashi ero AO actually
presential Vietnam to come up on the
state to find out the winner of our
special prise
today just one draw the luckiest one
draw
only focus focus pay attention please
[Music]
wow the number is two not yet
two all right let me
see
five who have two five and another
number what three oh 2 five3 what
else
254 okay we have four
what zero
7 257
258 oh my gosh let double check which
number
wow another two
five do you have another two
five six all right how about two five uh
Z 1 two right we have two five zero do
you have two five one
252 so the luckiest number of today is
two 5
2 please take C please please please say
come
252 do we have
it please stand to no one here oh my God
no
one do we have 2 52 first time no 2 52
second
time and two part two for the last time
all right cancel the
draw please help us to find oh my God so
nervous I'm so
[Applause]
nervous oh my God three
three who had
three
oh no one
7 I can see just shout out 9 7 six we
have already what
else Four 3 three all right
three
and
and the luest person
today is having the
number
three
oh oh my God please come to the stage
foration the smart guy with the the mini
game
right congratulations once
again
sorry
37 how
about you
have I'm sorry
307 I'm sorry here has
306 I'm so so sorry okay okay 307
307 307 congratulations just give it
thank you and I want like to invite Mr
maso atic at rud of Vietnam to
present the iPod to our lucky winner of
today
[Music]
congratulations thank you and Mr Edo
please remain on St all
right and once again congratulations to
all the lucky attendees winning the
prize today but we believe the most
valuable gift is the experience and
knowledge we've shared listen to and
learn together of the Vietnam actuario
conference
2023 and before concluding the program
we invite meter Masashi Edo appointed
actually fential Vietnam Assurance for
grab up speech welcome on the
[Music]
stage um did you enjoy
can you hear oh okay so I hope uh
everyone could enjoy tonight uh today uh
for this uh remarkable event and uh
maybe before I forget I should say thank
you to all the sponsors to enable this
uh event to happen and all the sponsors
uh if you don't mind please stand up and
get
Applause okay maybe
not many sponsors staying anymore uh
they have a schedule and we had some uh
several remarkable guest from The
Regulators but they have a schedule and
uh not any here but uh you know it was
uh very uh grateful to how those
people and uh next thing is that uh you
know organizers you know from my company
the presedential all the people you know
setups and you know hosting those things
were done by organizers maybe you guys
want to stand up
organizers
where
shy okay maybe uh maybe credential is a
very humble company okay um today that
we covered the uh lot of areas and uh
it's very remarkable the you know main
speech no other than the you know
opening remarks uh started from the
customer and uh next topic was about the
bank Assurance but still mostly about
customers then touches about
ESG not actual or topics at you know in
one sense but uh this is the uh area we
really need to think maybe actually is
as a pure you know St you know studied
perspective
uh people uh tend to think that you know
people as a life assured right but we
need uh kind of you know view that uh
you know those people are our customer
and that was uh really I believe that
reinforced such a
mindset and uh later this afternoon we
covered the advanced analytics and also
machine learnings yeah so those things
also at your flavor so nothing gives you
any answer itself but gave you a hint of
going forward so from that perspective
that we you can bring back uh those uh
things you touched today and maybe you
can further proceed your professional
career and another things um maybe more
important was that uh I saw
people are interacting socializing you
know before getting in here and uh that
excitement you know a little bit scared
our us the organizers because even if we
call you know nobody pays attentions and
stay outside and continue conversation
but uh that's a good indicator that you
know you guys are trying to you know
connect each other and uh sometimes we
you know view each other as a
competitors you know but uh we have a
common agenda to tackle so those are the
very good uh things we uh experience
today now I don't want to you know make
this piece so big and uh uh so maybe uh
last word is that uh safe trip back and
see you next year thank
you thank you so much Mr masatoshi for
your sharing today and now ladies and
gentlemen on behalf of the organizer we
would like to express our sincere
gratitude to own distinguished gu
speaker and actuario expert from various
insurance companies in Vietnam and the
region for attending the Vietnam
actuario conference 2023 today we would
like to spend a deep thanks to the guest
and sponsor Representatives Insurance
supervisory Authority in Insurance
Association Vietnam
RGA General reinsurance Swiss re Pacific
Life re Munich re scory and S OA and all
life insurance companies in Vietnam
market and we wish every success and all
the best to all insurance companies in
general and specificially to all
Actuarial here to a robust grow in the
upcoming era of the in sh industry in
2024 now goodbye and hope to see you
soon in the next Vietnam act to areial
conference
2024 thank you goodbye and see you
again all right thank you so much once
again for your attendance we also
provide you the free free ticket for
your vehicle parking please contact to
our organizer at the outside area for
the free ticket vehicle parking thank
you thank you so much once again thank
you so much and see you
again